(
"ai_sub_version": "2.9.1",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 7,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 15,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch"
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 5,
"max": 5,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
みんなの主食だよ。
It's everyone's staple food.
ご飯食べないと走れなくなる、みんな忘れないでよ。
If you don't eat, you won't be able to run. Don't forget, everyone!
やべえ！ それ基本ね！
Crap! That's basic stuff!
基本、基本。
Basic, basic.
ちょっと聞こえづらい？わたための声。
Is Watame's voice a bit hard to hear?
わー！
Yay!
あ、あ、あ、あ！
Ah, ah, ah, ah!
馬鹿にしてんのか！？あ、あ、あ！
Are you making fun of me?! Ah, ah, ah!
うわ、スバルちゃん待って、なんかハイレグだよ。
Whoa, wait, Subaru-chan, you're wearing a high-leg leotard.
バニーじゃん。 ハイレグやめて！
It's a bunny suit. Stop with the high-leg!
いや、間違ってないでしょ！わたためは黄色ハイレグで、スバルは黒ハイレグ！
I mean, I'm not wrong! Watame is wearing yellow, and Subaru is in black!
みんな、どっちがセクシー？どっちがセクシー？
Everyone, which one is sexier? Which one is sexier?
スバルか、わたためか、どっち？
Subaru or Watame, which one?
いや、やっぱりバニガかな、スバル。
Nah, definitely bunny girl, Subaru.
バニーガールには誰も勝てない。
No one can beat a bunny girl.
見せればいいってもんじゃないよ。
It's not just about showing it off.
バニーガールって言っても、わたためのことだからね。
Even if you say bunny girl, that refers to Watame, you know.
え、スバルは？ / スバルちゃんは...
Eh, what about Subaru? / Subaru-chan is...
ボタアン！
Botan!
みんなの声300%にしてみた。
I turned everyone's volume up to 300%.
300？300はでかいね。
300? 300 is huge.
これ以上上げられないくらい上げてる。
I raised it as much as possible.
こんちくわー！
Konchikuwa!
りおな！りおな！
Riona! Riona!
もう、刃物どもは終わり散らかしてる。
Those blades are running completely amok.
スバルボイス、みんな、音量...
Subaru's voice, everyone's volume...
あ、聞こえてる？
Ah, can you hear me?
ビビ！こんばんは！
Vivi! Good evening!
ビビ、こんばんは！ / あ、聞こえない？
Vivi, good evening! / Ah, you can't hear?
あ、ビビちゃん聞こえない？
Ah, Vivi-chan, I can't hear you?
聞こえてますか？
Can you hear me?
あ！聞こえてるよ！
Ah! I can hear you!
あ、聞こえてた！
Ah, you could hear me!
今なら歌を歌ってもバレない。
Even if I sing right now, nobody will find out.
よし、ビビ！
Alright, Vivi!
イェーイ！
Yay!
しらけん、みんな面白い。
Shiraken, everyone is so funny.
静かにしたほうがいいのかな？
Should we be quiet?
聞こえる？聞こえる？こっちちっちゃい？
Can you hear me? Can you hear me? Is my voice too quiet?
これ、大きくしたほうがいい？
Should I turn it up?
あ、なんかベビィに似合ってるよ。
Oh, it looks good on you, baby.
大丈夫？
Is it okay?
聞こえますか？
Can you hear me?
アキちゃんも似合ってる。
It suits Aki-chan too.
はーい。
Okay.
じゃあ、ちょっと説明、はい、します。
Alright, then I'll briefly explain things.
と言っても簡潔にしますね。
Though I'll keep it concise.
今日、ありがとうございます。
Thank you all for joining today.
ちょっと1時間、遅く始まってるんで...
Since we started about an hour late...
終了時間が今日1時までとなっておりますが、退出は自由なので...
today's end time will be 1:00 AM, but you can leave whenever...
何かご用事ある方は、あの、適宜抜けても大丈夫です。
so if you have other things to do, you can leave as needed.
はーい。
Okay.
で、えーと、普段、あの、株のルーレット、本来だったら21時から回してたんですが...
Also, normally we would spin the stock roulette starting from 9:00 PM...
1時間遅れているので、えーと、22時スタートになります。
but since we're an hour behind, it will start at 10:00 PM today.
おーい。/ はーい。
Okay.
で、そこから、はい、1時間ごとに、今日は22時、23時、24時に...
And from then, yes, every hour, today we will spin it at 10:00, 11:00, and 12:00...
の3回回すことになりますので、あの、株手に入れたい方は...
for a total of three spins. So if you want to get stocks...
えー、22時までに、まあ、ちょっと持っとくと、第1回目のルーレットが間に合うかなと思います。
if you have some by 10:00 PM, I think you'll make it in time for the first spin.
はーい。
Okay.
はい。で、職業の振り方は、その目の前の、あの、受付...
Yes. And as for distributing your job points, at the reception desk in front of you...
スキル受付の場所があるんですが...
where you can assign skills...
今日だけ、あの、リセット何回でもできます。
only for today, you can reset your points as many times as you want.
明日からは、1日1回なので。
From tomorrow on, it'll only be once a day.
はい。今日終了する際の、あの、職とか...
Yes. Your jobs when we wrap up today...
多分引き継ぎになるのかな？またちょっと後で連絡はしますが、お気をつけください。
will probably carry over. I'll contact you later about it, but please keep that in mind.
明日は1日1回です。
Tomorrow, it's only once a day.
なんか、なんかゴーゴーゴーって言ってる。
There's some roaring background noise.
ハウリングしてるかも。
It might be audio feedback.
はい、スピーカーが。
Yeah, the speaker.
で、あの、もし、何か分からないことあったら、もう気軽に呼んでください。
And if there's anything you don't understand, feel free to call me.
すぐ私向かえるんで、はい。
I can head over to help right away.
はーい。
Okay.
来てくれなかったら文功言っていいんですか？
Can we complain if you don't show up?
文功言ってもいいけどさー...
I mean, you can complain, but...
その後のこと考えろよ。大丈夫か？
you better think about the consequences. Got it?
おどしてる。
She's threatening us.
じゃあ、あと本当に何か分からないことあったり、困ったことあったら気軽に呼んでください。
So again, if you really don't understand something or get stuck, feel free to call.
はーい。
Okay.
では、以上です。もう、はい、散り散り、無職ども。行け行け。
Alright, that's all. Now disperse, you jobless folks. Go, go!
行こう行こう！
Let's go, let's go!
ダンジョンなの？
Is it a dungeon?
職業振り分け。
Job assignment.
振り分け係。
Assignment clerk.
どっち？
Which one?
職業...
Jobs...
ファーマー？
Farmer?
職業振り分け。
Job assignment.
ファーマーかな？
Maybe Farmer?
ファーマー？
Farmer?
ファーマーにしよう。
I'll go with Farmer.
ファーマー10。
Farmer 10.
ファーマー。
Farmer.
ギャンブラー？
Gambler?
今日振れるの？
Can we assign them today?
私は...
I'll...
ファーマー。
Farmer.
ファーマーか。
Farmer, I guess.
アルケミスト、かっこいい名前。
Alchemist is a cool name.
あ、オッケー。
Ah, okay.
アルケミスト。
Alchemist.
私はアルケミスト。
I'll be an Alchemist.
アリーナ？
Arena?
一旦、ファーマー。
For now, Farmer.
バトルダンジョンも...
Battle dungeon is also...
パズル？
Puzzle?
パズルやってみよう。
Let's try puzzle.
パズル。
Puzzle.
ファイター10にしといて、振り直せるんだよね。
I'll put 10 into Fighter, we can reset them later anyway.
アスレイベント。
Athletic event.
アスレチックとミニゲーム。
Athletic and mini-games.
ミニゲーム。
Mini-games.
道具。
Tools.
これ、どうやって買うの？
How do we buy things?
イナ。
Ina.
イナの頭。
Ina's head.
オッケー、とりあえず探してみよう。どこにあるのか。
Okay, let's just figure out where everything is.
あ、ここ？
Oh, here?
釣り。
Fishing.
フリーマーケット。
Free market.
まだ、何もないか。
Nothing here yet, I guess.
店。
Shops.
ちょっといいとこ探そう。
Let's find a good spot.
アルケミスト。
Alchemist.
ファーマー。
Farmer.
ここか。
Here it is.
あ、英語になってるの助かる。
Oh, it's in English. That helps.
助かる。読めないから。
That really helps, because I can't read Japanese.
あー、ね。
Ah, I see.
じゃ、な、何、何かをやるのがいいかな？
Well, what... what is it better to do?
じゃ、すーは、ま、一旦...
So, Su will, well, for now...
え、マジどうしたらいいんだ？
Wait, what should I seriously do?
え、本当に何も分かってない...
Wait, I really don't understand anything...
これって、普通で、こう...こうしてもいいんですよね？
You can just do this normally, right?
普通のマイクラの...
Like in normal Minecraft...
ことかな？
...I guess?
バッグ？
Bag?
あ。
Ah.
あ、Equipment slots.
Ah, Equipment slots.
いや、何もない。
No, there's nothing.
ご...5円。
Fi... 5 yen.
お。
Oh.
いいじゃん。
Nice.
木、木が欲しい。
Wood, I want some wood.
So basically, to explain to the English viewers, I guess...
...since, I guess, I'm the only English speaking member right now,
anything you do,
like collect and stuff, gives you...
...money.
There's three jobs and one sub-job. Sub-job is the...
...gambler.
And...
Ah, I wonder if it would have been best if I actually went...
...Alchemist for all of the mining stuff first,
and then set up my... set up a little base,
and then start farming, if you know what I mean.
ね？
Right?
最初は、アルケミストが良かったかもな。
Maybe Alchemist would have been better at first.
ま、今日は何回でも代われるから、
Well, since we can change as many times as we want today...
いいかも。
...it should be fine.
So, I think on the first day,
you can basically change anytime you want.
だから...
So...
アルケミスト始めて、ちょっと家とか作れたら
If I start as Alchemist and can build a house or something...
ファーマーになるのがいいかも。
...then maybe it's better to become a Farmer.
ウナ、ウナゴールド的な...
Something like Una, Una Gold...
え？
Eh?
うん、うん。
Yeah, yeah.
はい。
Yes.
で、じゃあ、その錬金アイテム、どこで手に入れるねん？ってなったら、
And then, "where do I get those Alchemy items?" you might ask...
怪しげな砂っていうものがあって、ダンジョンの中だったり、なんか砂漠とかにあったりして、
There's this thing called "Suspicious Sand" inside dungeons or in the desert...
おお。
Oh.
で、なんか、こういうね...
And like, this kind of...
ご、ごえん...
Five, five yen...
じゃなくて、
No, wait...
ご、ご、ゴールド？
G-G-Gold?
Cause it's go, go...
すみません。
Sorry.
で、
So,
いや、やっぱりこれがいいかな？
Well, maybe this is better?
念のため...
Just in case...
これも作ってもいいかも。
Maybe I should craft this too.
え、早く...
I want to get...
あれが欲しいんだよな。
...that thing soon.
あれと言うと...
By "that thing," I mean...
あれだよ。
...that thing.
あれなんです。
That's what it is.
知ってますか？
Do you know?
何と言うか、
What should I call it?
何だか、
Or like...
え、え、日本語難しいな。
Uh, Japanese is hard.
知ってるか？
Do you know?
知ってない？
You don't?
分かんない。
I don't know.
あれですよ、あれ。
It's that thing, that thing.
あれが大事なんですよ。
That thing is important.
あ、迷う
Ah, I might get lost.
Eleven.
Twelve.
Thirteen.
いいぞ、いいぞ
Nice, nice.
木は大事
Trees are important.
このシチュエーションの...
In this situation...
キーになるかも
...it might be key.
知らんけど
I don't know, though.
Twenty-four.
あ、りんご
Oh, an apple!
いや、最近日本暑くないですか？
Wait, hasn't Japan been hot lately?
ちょっと涼しくなったかも...
Maybe it's gotten a bit cooler...
なあ？
...right?
なーあ？
Right?
あ、あ、もう夜になっていく
Ah, ah, it's already turning into night.
どうしよう、家作る？
What should I do? Should I build a house?
でも、どこが良いか分かんない
But I don't know where a good place is.
まず...
First...
ボート
...a boat.
作れない？
Can't I make one?
何だっけ？
What was it again?
家欲しい
I want a house.
あ
Ah.
サンキュー、サンキュー。脳内の声
Thank you, thank you. Voices in my head.
え、これですね、ボート
Ah, this is it, a boat.
え、え、え、怖い、怖い
Ah, ah, ah, I'm scared, I'm scared.
どうしよう
What should I do?
ここで作る？
Should I build it here?
作っても良い？
Is it okay if I build it?
あ
Ah.
作っても良いぞ
I can build it.
いや、待とう。そんなに要らないかな？
Wait, let's hold on. Do I really need that much?
そんなに要らないかも
Maybe I don't need that much.
で
And...
ボタン先輩！
Botan-senpai!
えっと、こうして...
Let's see, do this...
いや、でも、なんかゾンビとか見えないかも？
But wait, maybe there aren't any zombies around?
大丈夫？
Is it safe?
かな？
Maybe?
大丈夫？
Is it safe?
いや、でも怖いんだもん。死にたくないんだもん。
But I'm scared. I don't want to die.
大丈夫かも。
Maybe it's safe.
いや、でも家はあった方が良いかもな。
But actually, it might be better to have a house.
ん？
Hm?
え... どこだろう？ My crafting table...
Eh... where is it? My crafting table...
どこ？どこだっけ？ あ、ここか。
Where? Where was it? Ah, here.
えい。
There.
で、家はドアが必要なんです。
And, houses need doors.
ここ、いなの... スタジオ... アパート。
This is Ina's... studio... apartment.
よし、もう一個作ろう。
Alright, let's make one more.
いいんじゃないですか？
Isn't this good?
ちょっと暗いんですけど、いなはあんまり気にしてないので。
It's a bit dark, but Ina doesn't really mind it.
うん、いいかも。
Yeah, maybe it's fine.
くらうー！
Growl!
うわ！
Whoa!
ハロー、イナ！
Hello, Ina!
ぺこら先輩！
Pekora-senpai!
わあ、暗闇！
Wow, darkness!
ライト！/ うわ！あ！
Light! / Whoa! Ah!
ライト！
Light!
おーいえす、がんばろーね、いなちゃん。
Oh yes, let's do our best, Ina-chan.
センキュー！
Thank you!
オッケー！
Okay!
ぺこ神！ぺこ神！火を...
Pekogod! Pekogod! Fire...
人間に火を... くださいました。
She gave... she gave fire to humans.
ああ...
Ah...
えー、いや、こ、こうしようかな？
Hmm, maybe I should do this?
ええと、あれを作る。
Let's see, I'll make that.
あれと言えば、あれなんですよね。
Speaking of that, it's that.
あの、あれあれ。あれ。これ。これこれこれ。
You know, that one, that one. That. This. This, this, this.
で、まずは...
And first...
いや、なんか... いな、やってるの逆じゃないですか？
Wait, isn't what I'm doing the opposite?
今考えたら、なんかアルケミストになろうと思ったら、ファーマーのことを考えるし。
Thinking about it now, if I wanted to be an alchemist, I'm thinking about being a farmer.
今ちょっとファームを作ろうと思ったら、もうアルケミストじゃん？
Now when I thought of making a farm, I'm already an alchemist?
あ、家か。
Ah, a house?
あ、こんにちは。
Ah, hello.
あ、家？家建てたの？
Ah, a house? Did you build a house?
お疲れ様です。
Good job.
すごい！おうちだ！
Wow, a house!
あ、何にもないんです。
Ah, there's nothing in here.
その発想はなかったな。
I didn't think of that idea.
かわいい！おうち。ご飯がない。
Cute! House... we have no food.
ご飯...
Food...
ご飯。
Food.
これ、もらっちゃダメなんかな？
Is it bad to take this?
これ？
This?
ダメだろ。
That's probably bad.
きたきたきた。
Here they come, here they come.
いや、でも、なんか... アルケミストのことをするためには、ご飯が必要ですね。
But still... to do alchemist things, food is necessary.
そうだ。
That's right.
ご飯大事。
Food is important.
お腹空いた。
I'm hungry.
いや、るーな先輩の声かわいい。
Wait, Luna-senpai's voice is cute.
可愛いな。
So cute.
いや、もっとちょうだい。
No, give me more.
ご飯。
Food.
ご飯...
Food...
ご飯だから... ご...
Because it's food... fo...
ご飯、ご飯...
Food, food...
えーっと...
Um...
いつも考えることなんですけど、なんか、エレベーター乗る時...
This is something I always think about, but like, when riding an elevator...
たまたま5階に止まるんじゃないですか。
...and it happens to stop on the 5th floor...
いつも思うんですよ。マネージャーちゃんとかに、
I always think about this. To my manager or someone,
5階に止まったら
if it stops on the 5th floor...
「ごかいです」と言いたかった。
...I wanted to say, "It's a misunderstanding." [Pun: 'Gokai' = 5th floor / Misunderstanding]
でも、どんなシチュエーションであれができるのかまだ、
But I don't know in what kind of situation I can use that yet...
まだ分かんない。今も考えてます。
I still don't know. I'm thinking about it even now.
So, basically, I was trying to explain...
...every time I get on the elevator. Cuz like, the Japanese elevator speaks, right?
And then every time it's like...
...land, stop, at the fifth floor,
it says "Gokai desu."
And then, that's also the same pronunciation as...
..."it's a misunderstanding".
So I'm like, "how can I ever make that joke to like, my manager or something?"
どのタイミングで使えばいいか分かんない。
I don't know at what timing I should use it.
どうですか、今のダジャレ？
How was that pun?
200 Yen already!
I'm rich!
あ、あれが必要だな。
Ah, I need that.
これ日本語で何だろ？あの、これ。
What is this in Japanese? Um, this.
Hoe?
Hoe!
く、鍬？
A ho... hoe? [Kuwa]
Oh, yeah, there's achievements and stuff.
鍬、鍬...
Hoe, hoe... [Kuwa, kuwa...]
詳しく教えて！
Tell me more in detail! [Pun: 'Kuwa' (hoe) -> 'Kuwashiku' (in detail)]
ね？ハハッ、ハハッ... すみません、すみません。
Right? Haha, haha... Excuse me, excuse me.
いや、何でこんなことになったか分かんない。
I really don't know why it ended up like this.
うん、いいじゃん。
Yeah, looks good.
えー、ご飯ができたら...
Ah, once the food is ready...
あの... あれですね... あれ
That... That's it... that...
あ、なんかショップで...
Oh, maybe at the shop...
あれ買えるかな？あの...
I wonder if I can buy that? Um...
アルケミストのショップはまだ見てない。
I haven't checked out the Alchemist shop yet.
ちょっと行ってみようか。
Let's go check it out.
どこだっけ？あっち？え？
Where was it? That way? Eh?
これで、なんか、昼ご飯食べれるかも。
Maybe I can eat some lunch with this.
1217円持ってるし。
Since I have 1,217 yen.
何で言ってることが違うの？
Why are you saying different things?
そんな殺生...
How cruel...
かわいいな。
So cute.
いいなー。
Nice~
うわぁ！
Whoa!
どう？なんか、分かんないことあったりする？
How's it going? Is there anything you don't understand?
まだ大丈夫です。
I'm still doing okay.
大丈夫？オッケー。なんかあったら呼んでね。
You're okay? Okay. Let me know if you need anything.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
はーい。あ、じゃあイナにちょっとニンジンあげとくよ。
Okay. Oh, let me give Ina some carrots.
おお！
Oh!
神様！
A god!
ありがとうね、来てくれて。
Thanks for coming over.
いや、こちらこそ、ありがとうございます。
No, thank you for having me.
楽しんでね。
Have fun.
なんか、色々、なんか...
Like, all sorts of things...
なんか今日は私だけが異邦人で...
Somehow, today, since I'm the only foreigner...
あ、本当だ。確かに。
Oh, that's true. Indeed.
なんか、マニュアルも、まあ英語でできて、本当にありがとう。
Thanks so much for making the manual in English too.
こんにちは、イエーイ、先輩！
Hello! Yay, Senpai!
ばんちょー！
Bancho!
冒険行った。
I went on an adventure.
はい、いってらっしゃい。
Alright, take care.
じゃあ、また何かあったら呼んでください。
Well, let us know if you need anything else.
はい、ありがとうございます！
Yes, thank you!
アルケミスト... いや、カタカナは読めてよかった。
Alchemist... Whew, I'm glad I can read Katakana.
ある！え、1000円、高っ！
They have it! Eh, 1,000 yen, so expensive!
高い！高い！
Expensive! Expensive!
買う？
Should I buy it?
お、500円...
Oh, 500 yen...
いや、でも、選ばないと...
No, but, I have to choose...
うわぁー！嘘でしょ！
Whoa! No way!
え、選ばないと。
I have to choose.
これ、ピックを買って...
I'll buy a pick...
うん、ピックを買って、釜は作る？...
Yeah, buy a pick, and craft the cauldron?
氷がない、氷がない。もう一回あれ、あれに行こうかな。
No ice, no ice. Should I go back there again?
これもっと安く買える？買えるのかな？
Can I buy this cheaper? I wonder if I can?
あ、違う。違う。
Ah, wait, that's not it. That's not it.
いや、これを使って、別のものを...
No, I'll use this to make something else...
作る。
I'll craft.
できた！
I did it!
おっけー。
Okay.
ありがと、おんまー。
Thank you, (mumbling).
よーし、どうも。
Alright, thank you.
勝ち続ければ...
If we keep winning...
わたちゃん先輩、ここに住んでますか？
Watame-senpai, do you live here?
ここに住んでるよ。
I live here!
隣ですね。
We're neighbors.
え、イナはどこ？
Eh, where is Ina?
あっちです。あの、あっち。
Over there. Um, that way.
あっち？
That way?
おー、あるんだ拠点、拠点が。
Oh, you have a base here.
あ、困ったら、いつでも聞きに来てね。
Ah, if you need help, feel free to ask anytime.
はい！
Okay!
お腹が空いてるんですけども...
Actually, I'm a bit hungry...
いくぞ。
Let's go.
Oh, wait. I have carrots. I can... I can plant the carrots.
神様の...
From the god...
間違えた。間違えた。
Ah, I made a mistake. I made a mistake.
いや、でも大丈夫。
No, but it's okay.
Wait, I have so much money now.
Economy.
Thank you, voices in my head.
Oh...
Okay, okay, okay, here's the plan. Here's the plan.
I'm going to get more wood.
Right, right, right. Maybe I should have some BGM.
And then, I'm going to go digging...
...for, uh, iron and stuff,
and diamonds, cuz as an alchemist, I think you get extra buffs to those.
But first, I need to get some food.
Oh, maybe I should plant more wheat.
Cuz I have seeds.
One, two, three, four, five, six... Okay, that's still good.
で、で...
And, and...
I can make a few bread.
Bread...
あ、イナだ。イナがいる。
Ah, it's Ina. Ina is here.
もらおう。ひひ。
I'll take it. Hee hee.
もらっちゃおう。
I'll take some.
木、もらいます。
I'll take some wood.
なんか、イナ、なんか家作ってんだけど何なんだろ？
It looks like Ina is making some kind of house, I wonder what it is?
イナ、イナ～
Ina, Ina~
イナ！何作ってんの？何作ってんの？
Ina! What are you making? What are you making?
あ、まぁ、最初は、あの、家を作って...
Ah, well, first, um, making a house...
おうち作ってんの？
Making a house?
はい。
Yes.
え、イナはさ、
Eh, Ina...
はい。
Yes.
職業何にしたの？
What job did you choose?
今は、アルケミストで、ちょっと、うん、
Right now, Alchemist, and once I...
ツールとか作ったら、ファーマーになるかな、と。
...make some tools, I think I'll become a Farmer.
え～、ちゃんと考えてるじゃん。
Wow, you've really thought it through.
はい。
Yes.
え、おうち見ていい？
Eh, can I look at your house?
あ、あ、まあ、いいですよ！
Ah, ah, well, sure!
え、ちょ、え、すごーい！
Eh, wait, wow, amazing!
ちょっと、まだ、まだ何もないんですけど。
There's still nothing inside though.
えーじゃあ、ちょっと白樺の苗木あげるよ。
Well then, I'll give you a birch sapling.
おお！あ、ありがとうございます！
Oh! Ah, thank you very much!
頑張ってね、イナ。
Good luck, Ina.
はい、ころね先輩もお、お気をつけて。
Yes, Korone-senpai, you take care too.
ありがとね！
Thank you!
はい。
Yes.
ゴミあげられたな...
She gave me trash...
Carrots!
Oh wait, the water doesn't reach here. Hm.
まいっか。
Well, whatever.
まぁいっか。
It's fine.
I'm winning! I'm winning! Look at all these seeds.
So much... So much money.
Is it time to invest?
Wait, hold on, let me look at the perks for Alchemist again. Uh...
アルケミストは...
Alchemist is...
Okay, okay. Okay, now that I have some food...
I can go mining a little bit. ちょっとだけ行ける。
I can go mining a little bit. Just a little.
Oh, but... these grow so fast!
早い。
So fast.
Okay. Can make three, no, four more bread.
Okay, that should be plenty.
Yeah, the growth rates are higher. Okay, there was... oh, I should get a...
Oh.
Wait, it doesn't really...
I forgot this is... There's no shaders.
I guess if there's no mobs, I don't really need... Who needs light anyways? We are creatures of the dark.
All right, all right, all right, all right. There was a cave here.
あ、誰か来てる？
Oh, is someone coming?
あ、ここじゃない？
Oh, isn't it here?
いや、でも暗いよ。
Yeah, but it's dark.
I need some coal.
何も見えない。
I can't see anything.
Oh, it's the glow thingamajigs.
Oh, someone was here.
暗いよ、怖いよ。
It's dark, it's scary.
まあ...
Well...
ここに行こうかな。
I guess I'll go here.
いや、でもコッパー...
But, copper...
これは日本語で何と言うんですか？コッパー。
What do you call this in Japanese? Copper.
イナの日本語レッスン！トゥトゥトゥトゥトゥトゥ。これは何？
Ina's Japanese lesson! Tu-tu-tu-tu-tu-tu. What is this?
これは、銅。
This is copper.
イナの日本語レッスンでした！トゥトゥトゥトゥトゥ。
That was Ina's Japanese lesson! Tu-tu-tu-tu-tu.
いや、でもアルケミストだったら、やっぱりあれやるのがいいかもですね。
Well, but if I'm an alchemist, maybe doing that is better.
えっと、ダイヤモンドのところまで行った方がいいかも。
Like, maybe it's better to go down to where diamonds are.
え、暗い。
Huh, it's dark.
何... えーと、マイナス... どこだっけ？見えない。
What... Uh, minus... Where is it? I can't see.
あ、32か。
Ah, -32.
I would like some coal though.
え、暗い。
Huh, it's dark.
ここで道迷ったらまずいかも。
If I get lost here, that might be bad.
いや、画面が暗くて、イナしか見えない。
Really, the screen is so dark, I can only see Ina.
と思ったら、それも悪くないんじゃないですか？
But thinking about it, isn't that not so bad?
うわっ！
Whoa!
え、え、どうしよう。
U-Uh, what should I do?
下に行くのいいけど、
Going down is fine, but...
ここで道迷ったら戻れなくなる。
if I get lost here, I won't be able to get back.
ご飯もあんまりないし。
I don't have much food either.
いたい。
Ouch.
なんか... あったらいいのに。
I wish... there was something here.
おお... おお... 怖い。
Oh... Oh... Scared.
どうしよう。
What should I do?
ここで、こうしたら、大丈夫。
If I do this here, it'll be fine.
見えないか、みんな。イナは見えてます。
Can't you see, everyone? Ina can see it.
え？
Eh?
でも何もない。
But there's nothing.
I want some coal.
ここを... うわっ！何？
Here... Whoa! What?
Y-17.
ちょっと明るくできるかな？
I wonder if I can make it a bit brighter.
ごめんなさい。
I'm sorry.
あ、いや、でもあんまり変わんないし。
Ah, well, but it doesn't change much anyway.
まあ、このままでいいか。
Well, I guess this is fine.
じゃ、ここで、え、右、左？どこ行く？
Then, here, uh, right or left? Where should I go?
右、右、右。
Right, right, right.
いや、今日、なんか釣りするつもりだったんですけど、
No, today, I was actually planning to go fishing, but...
まあ、
well,
行ける、大丈夫かな？
I can go, is it gonna be okay?
おお、おお。
Oh, oh.
My pickaxe will break.
I know, but I can't stop.
Oh, voices in my head. What is a good level for diamond again?
おお、金！
Oh, gold!
あ、やばい。あれだ、あれなんですよ。
Ah, oh no. That's it, that is it.
We are at depth minus 56.
遠い。
That's far.
いや、一回戻った方がいいかも。
Yeah, maybe I should go back once.
いや、
No,
金とかさ、
Gold, you know,
売れるんだっけ？
can I sell it?
いや、ここ、どこ？
Wait, where is this?
Okay, I'll go up when the pick breaks.
もうすぐ戻れる、うわー
I can go back soon, whoa!
暗い...
It's dark...
えっと今、OBS見てるんですけど...
Um, right now I'm looking at OBS...
何も見えない。
And I can't see anything.
いやでも、面白いですよね。
But still, it's fun, isn't it?
あ、戻った。え、ここからどこだっけ？
Ah, I'm back. Um, where do I go from here?
こっちか？
This way?
あ、でもここ、なんとなく...
Ah, but here, somehow...
何を...
What to...
木。
Wood.
ここだよって。
They say, "It's here."
ここで多分、出たはず。はい。
I should be able to get out from here. Yes.
天才！
Genius!
I would like some coal cuz it's kind of...
kind of really dark.
暗いよね。
It is dark, isn't it?
おお。
Oh.
ご飯。
Food.
オッケー、オッケー、オッケー。
Okay, okay, okay.
The thing is, should I...
should I go... wait...
I'm earning so much money from just farming.
Should I just farm?
Farmer... Farmer いいかも。
Farmer... Farmer might be good.
いやいやいや、でもダイヤ欲しい。
No no no, but I want diamonds.
そんなに行って、諦めるのは...
Giving up after going that far...
もったいない。
is a waste.
ピカピカストーン、持っていこう。
Let's go get the shiny stone.
おお。
Oh.
まあここは、誰かがもう行っているかも。
Well, maybe someone has already been here.
釣りは、また...
Fishing... again...
釣りしたかった。
I wanted to fish.
Ah, money to bank. You're right.
Oh!
Shulker box. Ah, これいいじゃん。
Shulker box. Ah, this is good.
Shulker box.
Farmer.
Ah, bucket. A bucket could be useful.
Fighter. Ah, 高い。
Fighter. Ah, expensive.
これだ。
This is it.
これでいいかも。
This might be fine.
Ah, maybe I should invest in the ATM.
これは、しろーぶず？
Is this Shiro-Boots?
1万円分くらい買っとく。
I'll buy about 10,000 yen's worth.
ししろ、泥建、うな電、大空建設、ネポラボ HD...
Shishiro, Doroken, Unaden, Oozora Construction, NePoLaBo HD...
あと5分か...
5 minutes left, huh...
わ、どうしよう...
Oh, what should I do?
まぁ、ちょっと試しに買ってみるくらいにするか...
Well, maybe I'll just buy some to test the waters...
ねー
Right?
500... 100円。
500... 100 yen.
うー、1万円の...
Hmm, 10,000 yen's...
1万円分だけやるわ。ちょっと、いったん様子見で。
I'll only do 10,000 yen. For now, I'll just see how it goes.
だから、1万円割る5...
So, 10,000 yen divided by 5...
2000円、2000円分ずつそれぞれ買ってみるか。
2,000 yen... Maybe I'll buy 2,000 yen's worth of each.
え、でもどっかに投資の方がいいのかな？
Wait, but is it better to just invest in one place?
どっかに一旦投資の方がいいのかな？
Is it better to just invest in one place for now?
Yes, it's good to have a diverse portfolio. Okay.
How much money do I have? Three...
Deposit.
Okay.
10万くらい入れよう。あ、それはやばい...
Let's put in about 100k. Oh, that's crazy...
銀行に3000円もあるんですよ。
I actually have 3,000 yen in the bank.
いや、ちょっと、何というか...
No, it's just, how do I put it...
今まで、日本の何という、その銀行...
Until recently, Japan's... what is it, that bank...
あれがなかったんですよ。
We didn't have that.
で、やっと作ったんですけど...
So, we finally made one, but...
まぁ、色々プロジェクトとかがあって...
Well, there are various projects and stuff...
なんか、お金入れるかなと思ったけど...
I thought about putting money in, but...
お金がない。
I have no money.
高いプロジェクトがあって...
Since there are expensive projects...
お金がない。
I have no money.
お金が入ってこない！
No money is coming in!
あ、これ必要。
Ah, I need this.
いや、いつお金、ちょっとだけ入れようかなと...
No, I was thinking when I should put in just a bit of money...
思ったんですけど...
but...
まだあまり外に出てないので...
since I haven't really been going outside...
何というか、そう。
how should I say, yeah.
When will I get paid? I don't know.
わからん。
I don't know.
でも全然大丈夫です。
But it's totally fine.
海外の銀行にはお金ありますので、
Because I have money in my overseas bank,
ちょっと、今の日本の銀行のあれがちょっと寂しいくらい。
it's just that my current Japanese bank account looks a bit sad.
で、初めてなんか作るとき、
And, when making something for the first time,
なんか、お金どれくらい入るんですかとか...
like, "how much money will I get?" and stuff...
問題があって、
there were some issues,
あ、ちゃんと答えたんですよ。
ah, and I answered them properly.
でも、
But,
何ヶ月お金が入ってこないから、
since no money has come in for months,
なんか銀行が「あれ？」ってなるかな？かも？
I wonder if the bank is going, "Huh?" maybe?
で、話でした。ちょっと面白いんじゃないですか？
So, that was the story. Isn't it kind of funny?
お話しあまりしないんですけど、
I don't talk about this kind of stuff much, but...
えー、大丈夫か、これ...
Ugh, is this gonna be okay...
おっけー。
Okay.
Okay, back to... back to my cave.
え、でも、ぜ、ゼロではない。大丈夫。
Uh, but, zero... it's not zero. It's okay.
ま、ずっとゼロだったらちょっとおかしいかもしれないんですけど。
Well, if it were always zero, that might be a bit weird, but...
ゼロ、ゼロではない。
It's not... it's not zero.
どこだったっけ？あれ？
Where was it? Huh?
あ、こっちか。
Ah, this way.
ルーレット？
Roulette?
あ、ルーレットか。あ、80、ルーレット。ルーレットどこだっけ？
Ah, roulette? Ah, 80, roulette. Where was the roulette again?
行きたい。見たい。みんな行ってる。
I want to go. I want to see. Everyone is going.
ギャンブルの時間。
It's gambling time.
え、え、え、見たい見たい見たい。
Eh, eh, eh, I want to see, I want to see, I want to see.
投資したほうがいいの？
Should I invest?
いや、この時のため、ギャンブラーになるのがいいかな？
Well, for times like this, maybe it's better to become a gambler?
わからない。
I don't know.
お次入れるわ、じゃあ。お、やったー！お次がある！お次がある！
I'll put it in next, then. / Oh, yay! There's a next one! There's a next one!
お次があるっていうこと？お次がある！
Meaning there is a next one? / There is a next one!
回しますよ！回しますよ！はーい！おねがいしまーす！
I'm spinning it! I'm spinning it! / Okay! Please!
じゃあ、ししろフーズから行くか。やだ！株来る！株来る！株！
Then, shall we start with Shishiro Foods? / No! Stock is coming! Stock is coming! Stock!
株！株！これが何？何だっけ？ししろフーズです！
Stock! Stock! / What is this? What was it again? / It's Shishiro Foods!
マイナス多いからね。今回マイナスになる... おおー！
There are a lot of minuses. / It's going to be minus this time... / Ooh!
+30！+30円！
+30! +30 yen!
ほんなら、泥建行きます！泥建！泥建！泥建！
Then, Doroken next! / Doroken! Doroken! Doroken!
マイナスになんないんだ、これ。下がる？下がる？安くなったら買うんだ。
It won't go to minus, this one. / Will it drop? / If it gets cheap, I'll buy.
こわ！おおー！泥建やばい！1.5倍。なるほどね。高くなってるね。
Scary! / Oh, Doroken is crazy! / 1.5 times. I see. It's getting expensive.
んな電鉄行きます！んな電鉄！どうなる？どうなる？
Luna Railway next! / Luna Railway! / What will happen?
どこ？どこだ？どこな？おおー！
Where? Where is it? Where? / Ooh!
また上がりましたね。やばい。ほんなら、大空建設行きます！
It went up again. Insane. / Then, Oozora Construction next!
下がる、下がる、下がる。上がれ！大空建設！大空建設！
Drop, drop, drop. / Go up! Oozora Construction!
安くなれ！安くなれ！サークル、サークル。
Get cheaper! Get cheaper! / Circle, circle.
きゃー！マイナス！
Kyaa! Minus!
マイナス200％ですね。えー！安くなった！
Minus 200%, indeed. / What! It got cheap!
ねぽらぼHD行きます！ねぽらぼホールディングス！強いよ。
NePoLaBo HD next! / NePoLaBo Holdings! / They are strong.
買えないよね。マイナスは買えないですね。マイナスは買えないです。
We can't buy, right? / You can't buy at a minus, right? / You can't buy at a minus.
うわー！おめでとうございます、+200％になりました！
Uwaah! Congratulations, it went to +200%!
次、23時です。今売らない方がいいの？このあと上がる可能性ないぞ、多分あんまり。
Next is at 23:00. / Is it better not to sell right now? / There's probably not much chance of it going up after this.
大空建設は買った方がいいの？このマイナス...
Should we buy Oozora Construction? This minus...
買えない！買えないよね。マイナス状態買えないですよ。
Can't buy! / You can't buy, right? You can't buy when it's in a minus state.
マイナス状態買えない。マイナスはプラスになるまで...
You can't buy in a minus state. / Until the minus becomes plus...
きゃー！ちょっと待ってよ。これさあ...
Kyaa! / Wait a minute. This...
どうする？どうしたらいい？これ。どれもみんなプラスだよ。ししろフーズ...
What should I do? What's the best move here? / Everything is in the plus. Shishiro Foods...
んな電がちょっとだけ上がったくらいで、もうなんか買わない方がいいのか。一回様子見るか。
Nna Railway only went up a little bit, so maybe I shouldn't buy anything else? / Let's wait and see for now.
ねぽらぼ建設で頑張りたい。頑張らせていただきたい。
I want to work hard at NePoLaBo Construction. Please let me work hard there.
え、どうなった？どうだった？株の変動注文は？全部プラス、ほぼ。
Wait, what happened? How was the stock change order? / Almost everything is in the plus.
え、ねぽらぼが...跳ねた？跳ねた。跳ねました。
Oh, NePoLaBo is... / Did it jump? / It jumped. It jumped up.
あ、買っててよかった！Ah, wait. I ended up buying.
Ah, I'm glad I bought some! / Ah, wait. I ended up buying.
売却して2万。やばい。売るか。ま、いっか。
Sold them for 20,000. / Crazy. / Should I sell? Well, whatever.
ま、いっか。バイ、バイ。
Well, whatever. Buy high...
So low...
や、だから...
Yeah, that's why...
卵？
Eggs?
だから株とか、あんまり自分でやってないんですよ。
That's why I don't really do turnips myself.
プロに任せた方がいい。
It's better to leave it to the professionals.
みんなもプロに任せてます。
Everyone else leaves it to the professionals too.
いや、お金とかさ、みんなあまり分かんないんですよ。
I mean, we don't really understand money and stuff.
なんか、ご飯食べれるくらいだったら、いい。
As long as I can make enough to buy food, that's fine.
食べて、たまたま楽しいことやれるくらいのお金があったら、いい。
As long as I have enough to eat and occasionally do fun things, it's fine.
あ、こっちか。
Ah, this way?
おい...
Whoa...
Okay, I'm ready.
戻りますよ、暗い世界に。
I'm returning... to the dark world.
今回は、出れなくなるかも。
This time, I might not be able to get out.
ね？そうですね、楽しいのが一番大事っていうか。
Right? That's right, having fun is the most important thing, I guess.
どの仕事しても、楽しい仕事やりたい。
No matter what job, I want to do a fun job.
え、ここ？もうここ？
Eh, here? Already here?
え、もう戻った？早い。
Eh, already back? That was fast.
暗い...
It's dark...
お、レッドストーン。
Oh, redstone.
いや、残した方が良かったかな？
Wait, would it have been better to leave it?
え、怖い。
Eh, scary.
広いから怖いね。どこだったっけ？
It's big, so it's scary. Where was it?
ここか。
Here?
木があったら、ここだよって。
If there's wood, it shows "here it is."
日本も同じかな、あのヘンゼルとグレーテル。
Is it the same in Japan? Like Hansel and Gretel...
このパンの、あれを残して、行く話。
The story where they leave breadcrumbs behind as they go.
I tried to make an arrow, I'm not sure if that'll make sense.
同じ。これなんです。これが、イナの...
Same. This is it. This is Ina's...
これ。
This.
ちょっと大きいんですけど。
It's a bit big, though.
大きいけど、あれなんです。これがあったら家に戻れる。
It's big, but that's what it is. With this, I can return home.
27...
ていうか、何にもないわ。
Actually, there's nothing here.
ここか？
Here?
ここにする。
I'll do it here.
これ、いける？
Can I go through here?
いけない。
No, I can't.
暗く...暗くなった。
It's dark... it got dark.
え？え？
Huh? Huh?
ゾンビおるじゃん！
There's a zombie!
何？
What?
行きたくない。
I don't want to go.
じゃあ、ここで...
Well, from here...
ここで下に行く？
Should I go down from here?
ここちょっと、壁を作って...
Let me make a wall here...
ここは行けない。
Can't go this way.
で、ここで...
So, here...
マーキングをして。
let's make a marking.
そう。
Yes.
で、ここから行く。
And let's go from here.
マイナス、何だっけ？
Minus... what was it again?
もう覚えてない。
I don't remember anymore.
50...57だっけ？
50... was it 57?
56？
56?
いや。
No.
いける。
I can do this.
いや、なんか...
Wait, is it...
明るくなってる？
getting brighter?
気のせい？
Just my imagination?
38。
38.
Do I speak English too? A little bit.
おっ。
Oh.
Oh, it's bright, maybe I should leave it.
That was the sound for a cave, right?
おっ、もうすぐじゃん。
Oh, almost there.
52...
55...
56...
ここから右。
From here, to the right.
Pika pika stone~
来ないかな？
Is it not coming?
Can Towa just buy it?
But it's different!
あつまるのは、なんか two over, right?
Collecting them is like... two over, right?
違うんだよ
No, that's not it.
自分の手で作るの
Creating it with your own hands...
その気持ちの意味は分かるかい
Do you understand the meaning of that feeling?
欲しい、ピカピカストーン
I want... shiny stone.
いや、本当に出る？出ない？
No, will it really show up? Or not?
あ、ゴールド
Oh, gold.
みんな、Only Yen。そう、I think so.
Everyone's like, "Only Yen." Yeah, I think so.
Redstone torches... do they work?
How do you make it again?
Are they bright enough?
They are! You're a genius!
暗くない！
It's not dark!
暗い...
It's dark...
いや、いっぱい作ろうか。
No, let's make a lot of them.
いや、4つしかない。
Wait, I only have four.
光よ...
Light...
ピカピカストーン
Shiny stone...
光ってくれ
Please shine...
I don't think off-hand works because we don't have any, uh, shaders.
光よ...
Light...
ピカピカストーン！
Shiny stone!
いや...
No...
あの、お隣さんですけど...
Um, what about the neighbors...
ないんですか？もう、もうないんですか？
Is there none? Is there really no more?
あの、いや、3つあるんですけど...
Um, well, I have three, but...
もうちょっと...
A little more...
もう、もうちょっとないんですか？
Is there, is there not a little more?
あの...
Um...
もう、もういいや。
F-Fine, whatever.
いや、これは進むしかない。
No, I just have to move forward.
希望はある。多分。
There is hope. Maybe.
あ、何かクエストとかあった気がする。
Ah, I feel like there were quests.
ありますよね。
They exist, right?
何か、スペシャルクエストとかあったと思うんですけど。
I thought there were special quests...
これかな？あ、これか。モンスターハンター。
Is it this one? Ah, this is it. Monster Hunter.
アイアン。これはやったし、モンスターハンターとこれか。
Iron. I did this one, so it's Monster Hunter and this one.
これ、多分アイアン、アイアン、アイアン...
This probably says iron, iron, iron...
オーをマインして、って。もう、まあアイアン見たことないんですけど。
to mine the ore. Well, I've never actually seen iron.
アイアンよりピカピカストーンが見つかったんですけど。
I found shiny stone instead of iron, though.
アイアン... アイアンって何だっけ？Y座標？
Iron... What was iron again? The Y-coordinate?
ちょっと高かった気がする。
I feel like it was a bit higher.
Was iron like 17 or something? 16?
Minus 16 or 16?
アイアン。
Iron.
気をつけないと。
I have to be careful.
じゃあ、ここで。いっか。
Okay, let's do it here.
いや、ちょっと溶岩は怖い。
No, lava is a bit scary.
え、近い。
Eh, it's close.
え？左？
Eh? Left?
え？上？上かも。
Eh? Up? Maybe up.
上かな？
Up?
いや、でもこれあるから...
No, but since I have this...
何となくこれは作れる。
Somehow I can make this.
いいね。
Nice.
溶岩があるところにダイヤがあるんですけど、
Diamonds are usually where lava is, but...
ちょっと怖いな。
it's a bit scary.
いや、もうそろそろか？いや、でも...
No, is it about time? But still...
I can make a pickaxe if I need.
ピカピカストーンがある。
There is shiny stone.
ダンジョン可能になりました。お。
Dungeons are now available. Oh.
え、スティックがない。
Eh, I don't have sticks.
え、みんな大丈夫かな？
Eh, is everyone okay?
Is it a... connection?
ピカピカ、ピカストーン。どこどこ、ピカストーン。
Shiny, shiny, shiny stone... Where are you, shiny stone?
Oh, is it dungeon? Ah, oh, I guess it's like a whole different server thing?
あ、ダンジョンがクラッシュ。なるほどなるほど。
Ah, the dungeon crashed. I see, I see.
ピカピカ、ピカストーン。暗いからちょっと見えないね。
Shiny, shiny, shiny stone... It's dark, so I can't see much.
ピカピカ
Pika pika...
...ストーン
...stone.
おっか、BGMも忘れたか？
Oh, did I forget background music too?
BGMあったほうがいいですか？なくても大丈夫ですか？
Is it better to have BGM? Or is it fine without?
Do you guys want BGM? I am the BGM.
Bring your own BGM.
ピカピカストーン、please...
Pika pika stone, please...
お、ラピス。
Oh, lapis.
いや、ちょっと違うけど。
Well, it's a bit different, but...
まあ、いいか。
Oh well, whatever.
お！
Oh!
おお！おお！
Oh! Oh!
なんと。
What a surprise...
ああ、釣り…できるかも？
Oh, maybe I can go fishing?
今日、釣りできるかも。
Maybe I can fish today!
いや、モブはいないんですよね。
Ah, there are no mobs here, right?
釣りできるかも。
Maybe I can fish...
やった！やった！でもここでなんかレアなことがあるかもしれない。
Yay! Yay! But there might be something rare here.
おお！
Oh!
おお、おお、おお。
Oh, oh, oh.
おお、おお。
Oh, oh.
いいじゃん、ああっ！
Awesome! Ah!
お、ラヴァ。
Oh, lava.
いいな。 / うわあ！
Nice. / Whoa!
神ちゃんがさ、真っ黒な、真っ黒な中、イナがあれしてるから、懐中電灯をあげてくれないかって言われた。
Kami-chan was like, "Ina is playing in pitch black, in pitch black. Can you give her a flashlight?"
あれ？たいまつ持ってる？持ってない？ / あ、多分、持ってない。
Huh? Do you have torches? Or you don't? / Ah, probably... I don't.
持ってない？あ、ここ明るくなってないか。あ、確かに。ちょっと待ってね、たいまつ渡しとこうか。
You don't? Ah, isn't it dark here? Ah, indeed. Wait a sec. Let me give you some torches.
リスナーさんが「イナが真っ黒」「配信が真っ黒です」って言ってて。
The viewers were saying, "Ina is pitch black," "the stream is pitch black."
いや、でも私は普通に…なんていうか、暗いの好きなので、大丈夫かなと思って。
Well, but normally, how should I say... I like the dark, so I thought it'd be fine.
本当？リスナーがね、「イナが…イナの配信真っ黒だよ」って。
Really? But the viewers said, "Ina's stream is pitch black."
いや、なんかごめんなさい、リスナーさん。
Ah, sorry about that, viewers.
いいよ、いいよ。が…頑張って冒険してね。 / ありがとうございます。
It's fine, it's fine. Keep up the good work on your adventure! / Thank you very much.
ほなー。
Bye-bye.
いや、なんか、ふふふ。
Well, somehow... hehehe.
ちょっと見えないんですけど、イナ今、赤…赤くなりました、顔が。恥ずかしい！ばれてる。
You can't see it, but Ina's face turned red just now. How embarrassing! They found out.
あ！ピカピカストーン！
Ah! Pika pika stone!
イナの冒険がばれてる。
My adventure's secret is out.
ていうか...
Or rather...
あ、ありがとうございます、いろいろ。
Ah, thank you very much for various things.
あ、ご、ごめんなさいね、真っ暗で。
Ah, s-sorry about it being pitch black.
これからは見えますよ。
From now on, you will be able to see!
あ！来たー！できたー！
Ah! It's here! I did it!
いや、これ... あ、できた？ん？ん？
No, this... Ah, I did it? Huh? Huh?
Is it smelting an iron?
あれかな？
Maybe that's it?
あ、来たー！
Ah, it's here!
やったー！
Hooray!
Smelting... smeltingですね。
Smelting... It's smelting, isn't it?
SmeltingはIRySの得意のdish。
Smelting is IRyS's specialty dish.
なんでこう喋ってるのか分かんない。
I don't know why I'm talking like this.
えー、何使うんだっけ？
Uh, what do I use again?
これも使えるんだっけ？使えない。木！はい。
Can I use this too? I can't. Wood! Okay.
Iron作ります。
I'll make iron.
作りました！
I made it!
で...
And...
またできていないです。
It's still not completed.
なんだろう？
What could it be?
Google先生教えて！
Google-sensei, tell me!
えー、日本語、英語...
Uh, Japanese, English...
Mining iron ore... できたのに、どうして？
Mining iron ore... Even though I did it, why?
Normal stone iron ore instead of deepslate... あー！
"Normal stone iron ore instead of deepslate..." Ah!
そうですね！
That's right!
I might as well smelt all of this so I can...
...possibly make more iron tools.
Although my diamond pickaxe is lasting a while.
Maybe I can make a sword so I can hunt a monster.
Who are you, could you be, baby...
Nya nya nya nya nya nya...
In the mirror... nya nya nya...
おお！
Oh!
There is more here desu.
There is more here.
おお！
Oh!
More redstone desu.
More redstone.
Oh, lava desu.
Oh, lava.
広いデス。
It's spacious.
Oh! String! String...
おお！
Oh!
Peka-peka stone!
Shiny stone!
Oh! Peka-peka stone!
Oh! Shiny stone!
Peka-peka stone!
Shiny stone!
素晴らしい。
Wonderful.
Peka-peka stone!
Shiny stone!
Oh! Water!
Oh! Oh! Iron!
Sorry... sorry...
あれ？どこだっけっけ？ここ？
Huh? Where was it again? Here?
道迷ったりしないですからね、イナは。
Ina doesn't get lost, you know.
これはすべて計画通りですね、はは！
This is all according to plan, haha!
えー、えっと...
Uh, let's see...
ここは？
How about here?
おお、アイアン！わー！
Oh, iron! Wow!
ここかな？
Is it here?
あは！
Aha!
ね！計画通りなんですよ。見てください。
See! It's all according to plan. Look at this.
ちょっとマーキングしよう。
Let's mark this spot.
ここだって。
It's here.
あれ作ろうか。
Shall I make that?
Iron sword... fit for a hero.
But alas, I lack a stick.
これするか。
Let's do this.
で... で...
And... and...
ちょっとここに...
Let's put this here...
これを、ほい、ほい、ほい、ほい...
This... hop, hop, hop, hop...
ほい、ほい、ほい。
hop, hop, hop.
よし。
All right.
はい！はい、はい、はい、はい。
Yes! Yes, yes, yes, yes.
わあ！
Whoa!
呼んだ？ / あ、いえ。
Did you call? / Ah, no.
ん？ / なに？呼ばんでないだと？ / 呼んでないです。
Hmm? / What? You didn't call? / I didn't call.
嘘！イナちゃんがクエストで困ってるよってめっちゃ言われたぞ。
No way! I was told so much that Ina-chan is struggling with a quest.
あ！クエストですか？あれ？あの...
Ah! The quest? Huh? That...
あ、モンスターハンターの下の... / うん。
Ah, the one under Monster Hunter... / Yeah.
あの、アイアン... あれ？ / 鉄の鉱石を掘る？
Um, iron... Huh? / Mine iron ore?
はい！あれってなんか、普通の石の、石にある...
Yes! Is that like, in normal stone, the one that is in stone...
そうそうそうそう。そうです。
Right, right, right, right. Yes, it is.
うん、うん、うん。そうだと思いました。
Yeah, yeah, yeah. I thought so.
おけ、おけ、おけ。 / はい、はい、はい、はい。
Okay, okay, okay. / Yes, yes, yes, yes.
ありがとう。 / ありがとうございます。すみません。
Thanks. / Thank you very much, sorry.
てんきゅー。いいよ、いいよ、いいよ。
Thank you. It's fine, it's fine.
掘ってる？めっちゃ掘ってる、ここ。 / はははは！
Are you mining? You've mined a ton here! / Hahahaha!
めっちゃ掘る。 / えへ、えへ。
You mine so much. / Ehe, ehe.
へー、すごい。なんかもう拠点みたいになってんじゃん。
Wow, amazing. It's already looking like a base.
いや、ここなんか広くて... / 広いね。
Well, it's kind of spacious here... / It is spacious.
ずっといました、はい。 / へー。すごい。
I've been here the whole time, yes. / Whoa, cool.
え、すご。あれだね。なんか、もともと坑道だったとこかな？
Wow, amazing. This must be... Was this originally a mine shaft?
はい、はい、はい。 / いいじゃん。
Yes, yes, yes. / Nice.
似合うよね、イナね。 / はははは！
It suits you, Ina. / Hahahaha!
こういう場所がなんか...
A place like this, somehow...
あ、ここ家にしようかな？ちょっと街遠いですけど。
Ah, maybe I should make this my home? Though the town is a bit far.
いや、 demo chotto machi no chikaku itta hou ga minna no... / 嘘です、はは！
Well, but it's probably better to go near the town for everyone's... / Just kidding, haha!
たまには街にも来てねってなっちゃう。 / あ、はいはい、もちろんデス。
Otherwise we'll be like, 'Come to town once in a while!' / Ah, yes, yes, of course.
あ、おけおけ。じゃ、またなんかあったら呼んで。 / あ、はい！ありがとうございます！
Ah, okay okay. Well, call me again if anything happens. / Ah, yes! Thank you very much!
ばいばい！ / ばいばい！
Bye bye! / Bye bye!
いや、呼んでないですけど！
Wait, I didn't call her though!
大丈夫だよ、イナ。こう分かってるって... 恥ずかしいんだもう。
It's fine, Ina. I know that... I'm so embarrassed.
なんかこういうことってさ... あれ、あれみたい...
You know, this kind of thing... It's like, like...
はい。なんか、家で一人の、いるときさ...
Right. Like, when you're alone at home...
なんかめっちゃ、一人でカラオケしていて...
and you're doing karaoke all by yourself...
なんか、後ろ見たら、家族が、家に帰って...
and when you look behind you, your family has come home...
ちょっと、静かにして見ている？
and they're quietly watching you?
それ、それ、それなんだよ！
That's, that's, that's what it is!
ねえ、なんか...
Hey, like...
一人で、ピカピカストーン、ピカピカストーン、するとき...
when you're doing "pika pika stone, pika pika stone" all by yourself...
家族が見たら、どうする？
and your family sees you, what do you do?
恥ずかしいんだよ。
It's so embarrassing.
はい。じゃあ、まだ行ってない場所ある？
Okay. Then, is there any place I haven't been to yet?
ここも大丈夫。
Here is fine too.
よし。
Alright.
でも楽しいね。なんか...
But it's fun. Like...
生きているだけで、お金、お金とかもらえるって、いい、いいことだよね。
just by being alive, getting money, getting money is a good, good thing, isn't it?
羨ましい、この世界。
I'm jealous of this world.
ここで...
Here...
はい、見てくださいね。
Yes, please look.
ここで...
Here...
ここ、じゃなくて...
Not here, but...
ええ、ここで...
Yeah, here...
ね？
Right?
えっと、ここ行って...
Let's see, go here...
あ、あ,あ,あ,あ...
Ah, ah, ah, ah, ah...
ここ...
Here...
あれ？ここ、ここもある？
Huh? Here, is there this place too?
ここ登ったら...
If I climb up here...
すぐに戻って...
going back immediately...
これがあって...
we have this...
ええ...
Yeah...
あっちか。
Over there, huh.
ここで...
Here...
ここか。
Is it here?
ここだよね。
It's here, right?
うん、うん、ここで...
Yeah, yeah, here...
そうそうそう、ここだよここだよ！
Right, right, right, it's here, it's here!
これもお金...
Is this money too...
高いかな？
I wonder if it's expensive?
水持って...
Holding water...
持ってない。
I don't have it.
まあ、まあ。
Well, well.
おお。
Oh.
売るかな、これ？なんか、家綺麗に...
Should I sell this? Like, to make the house pretty...
できますよ、てか、っていうか...
you can do it, or rather...
I'm not gonna come back here though.
いや、でも、家な、紫ですからね。家を紫にするのも悪くないかも。
But still, my house is purple, you know. Making the house purple might not be too bad.
They're all 1 yen.
So pretty.
まあ、いいかな...
Well, it's fine...
そんなに欲しくないし。
I don't really want it anyway.
あっ。
Ah.
うん。
Yeah.
で、どこで戻れるんだっけ？ここかな？
Now, how do I get back? Is it here?
うん、ここだよ。
Yeah, it's here.
Ah, my cookie crumbs! My breadcrumbs!
Yeah!
いや、20... 26 あったら、あれ作れるんじゃない？
No, if I have 20... 26, can't I make that?
いや、1回戻るか。
No, let's head back once.
もうすぐあれだし。
Since it's almost time for that.
あの...
You know...
あれですよね、ルーレット。15分くらい。
That, right? The roulette. In about 15 minutes.
や、ここ好きですか？
Well, do you like it here?
イナは...
Ina...
ここに... ここで住んでもいいんですよ。
...could live here... live here, you know.
暗いし、いいんじゃないですか？
It's dark, so isn't it nice?
いや、この世界でも引きこもったらどうしよう。
No, what if I become a shut-in in this world too?
Torch, please.
まあ、まあ、まあ...
Well, well, well...
暗いところに慣れてもいいんじゃないですか？
Isn't it fine to get used to dark places?
いいんじゃないですか？
Isn't it fine?
Oh.
いいですね。
That's nice.
何？
What was that?
There's a stone pickaxe task before the iron...
Ah, なるほど。So wait, so technically, perhaps...
Ah, I see. So wait, so technically, perhaps...
as a theory...
If we make a stone pickaxe...
Not this one, that's tuff. Ah, tuff life.
これか。
This one.
じゃない？
Right?
まあ、まあ、まあ。We'll figure it out. We'll go hunt for iron after we get to the surface.
Well, well, well. We'll figure it out. We'll go hunt for iron after we get to the surface.
この暗い世界は...
This dark world is...
こう...
Like this...
まあ、まあ、まあ。It's so bright. Ah.
Well, well, well. It's so bright. Ah.
明るい！
It's bright!
光が... ひ、光が...
The light... th-the light...
見える。
I can see it.
え、ここじゃない、ここだ。ここなんですよ。
Eh, not here, here. This is the place.
ひ、光！
L-light!
あ、戻った！
Ah, I'm back!
戻ったー！
I'm back!
戻ったし...
I'm back...
Return to civilization, haha.
あー、いいね。
Ah, nice.
みゃむ、みゃむ、みゃむ...
Myaum, myaum, myaum...
ださ。
How lame.
でも、やるしかねえ。
But I've gotta do it.
あ、みゃう？
Ah, meow?
What do you mean "meow"?
にゃこ？
Nyako?
お、ゴールドYAGOO。
Oh, Gold YAGOO.
いいね、ゴールドYAGOO。
Nice, Gold YAGOO.
I do kind of want to try the puzzle, though. I think... I think the easy one, you can do it by yourself, too.
あー。
Ah.
ぽい。
Plop.
オッケー。
Okay.
あー。
Ah.
ぽい。
Plop.
オッケー。
Okay.
Oh, many carrots.
I have so many, I don't have to carrot about food anymore, hehe.
え。
Eh.
オッケー、オッケー、オッケー、オッケー。
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
Oh, so many carrots.
I can leave this there.
I do want to get Monster Hunter, though, so... make one sword... and pants...
...and helmet.
And shoes.
あ。
Ah.
Just enough!
イェー！
Yeah!
See? Hand-made.
Wonderful, wonderful.
Okay.
Put that there.
Uh-huh, uh-huh.
We have iron.
I should get more wood, huh? I should plant more wood, actually.
あ。
Ah.
So more people can use wood.
うん、うん、うん...
Uh-huh, uh-huh, uh-huh...
Okay, with the iron, I will make an axe.
And I can get more wood.
すばらしいですね。
Wonderful, isn't it?
Stone pickaxe, I'll leave it here. This and this, I'll also leave there.
Oh, I forgot. I should... I don't know if I should buy more stocks, though, 'cause everything is high right now.
We'll just finish mining these, so the leaves despawn.
Wait, but more importantly...
(gasp)
つり...
Fishing...
できる。
I can do it.
Wait, we should also make a shield if we want to hunt monsters.
I think we can go to the arena and stuff, or dungeon.
Okay.
We have shield, I have sword, I have fish.
Oh...
More trees. Tree good.
Another person forgot to mine a tree there.
I don't think you can buy negative... stocks.
What I will do is deposit some money.
(gasp)
Wait, I can deposit more.
Lamb Vegas?
No, resist.
No, resist!
I mean, I bought stocks last time, so we'll see if it... raises or not.
スキルも武器もないし。
[Miko] I don't have skills or weapons either.
フリーマーケット。何かあるかな？
Flea market. I wonder if there's anything?
おお。
Oh.
ふむ。
Hmm.
なんか忘れちゃった。
[Miko] I forgot something.
ね、あ、ダンジョンか。確かに。行く？
[Miko] Hey, oh, a dungeon? Indeed. Going?
おお。
Oh.
調達しようかな？
[Miko] Should I go supply up?
100,000?
25個買っちゃった。
[Korone] I bought 25 of them.
うわ、無駄かな、これ。
[Korone] Wow, is this a waste?
うわ、最悪。
[Korone] Wow, this is the worst.
焼きたら、焼きたらに金払っちゃった。
[Korone] Cooked cod... I paid money for cooked cod.
おお。
Oh.
いやあ。
Man...
ルーレット、2回。
Roulette, two rounds.
いや、弓、ファーマーになるかな？
Well, bow... I wonder if I should become a farmer?
1時間残ったし。
I have one hour left anyway.
鮭もあるんだよ。
[Watame] There's also salmon.
鮭とタラどっちが好き？
[Miko] Which do you like better, salmon or cod?
おお。
Oh.
で、釣りをするのです。
And so, I will do some fishing.
どうですか？
How about this?
いいプランじゃないんですか？
Isn't it a good plan?
Bee Keeping unlocked...
あ。
Ah.
で...
And...
バトル？
Battle?
いや、バトルEasyだったら、い、いけるんじゃない？
Well, if it's Battle Easy, I could probably go, right?
ダイヤだし。
Since I have diamond gear.
じゃ、じゃじゃじゃじゃ...
Well, well, well...
これで、ファイターになるんです。
With this, I will become a Fighter.
で、バトル、行く。
And, battle, go.
なんだっけ？
What was it?
バトル、チームメンバー募集を... してきました。スタートをクリックしてください。
Battle, team member recruitment... is active. Please click Start.
おっ。
Oh.
うーん、プロシード。
Hmm, proceed.
これか。
Is it this?
お、もう、もう行ってもいいんですが、あ！
Oh, can I, can I go now? Ah!
もう始まった？
Has it already started?
パン。
Bread.
お、スポーンするんですか？ ここで。
Oh, do they spawn here?
パン。
Bread.
えい！
Take that!
パン。
Bread.
なんか目的...
Like, the goal...
あう！あう！
Ouch! Ouch!
おおー！
Ooh!
Free diamond sword.
パン。
Bread.
No revelation here.
パン。
Bread.
上に行くのか？
Do I go up?
目的？
The goal?
Yes! Kill each other!
えい。
Take that.
パン。
Bread.
あう！
Ouch!
パン。
Bread.
I have a timer. I know, I know!
あ、もっと上に行ける。
Ah, I can go further up.
パン。
Bread.
えい。
Take that.
えい、えい。
Take that, take that.
パンしかねぇな。
Nothing but bread.
他に、ここか？ ほい、ほい。
Elsewhere... here? Up, up.
パン。
Bread.
ない？
Nothing?
ええー？ 多いなぁ...
Ehh? There's so many...
うおー！
Whoa!
パン。
Bread.
「鍵が必要だ」これですか？
"A key is required..." Is it this?
キーって、鍵？鍵？
Key... as in key? A key?
モンスターから出るかな？
Do they drop from monsters?
あ！
Ah!
出たかも？
Did it drop?
いや...
No...
いや、あれってレベルアップの...
No, that's for leveling up...
チェスト？
Chests?
全部、見ちゃダメなん...
Should I not look at all of them?
いや、クリーパー来ないかな
Man, I hope a creeper comes.
あー！
Ahhh!
ここだっけ？ここ？
Was it here? Here?
パン
Bread.
あ！クリーパーばっかり！
Ah! It's nothing but creepers!
おあっ！おあっ！
Whoa! Whoa!
え、どこ... どこまで見てないんだっけ？
Wait, where... where have I not checked yet?
どこだっけ？
Where was it?
あー！
Ahhh!
ごめんなさい！
I'm sorry!
おっ
Oh.
これ？いや...
This? No...
上？
Up?
もう時間ない！
There's no more time!
えっ
Eh?
あ、消えた... 消えた。じゃ、ここ戻る
Ah, it's gone... it's gone. Okay, going back here.
ここ？
Here?
おー！
Whoa!
なんじゃ... おー！
What is... Whoa!
Netherite.
え、鍵... 鍵じゃないんですけど
Wait, a key... It's not a key, though.
え？え？
Eh? Eh?
じゃ、これでもなかったらどっち？
Then, if it's not this one, which is it?
Maybe this wasn't it for me.
I don't think I checked these... oh, I did.
I'm blind.
え？
Eh?
これは？うーん
This one? Hmm.
There's another...
Ah, I'm cornered!
There's another... found the netherite armor.
Is that it over there? Where was it? Where did I find the netherite armor? It was over there.
いや、もう... クリーパー手伝って！
Oh, come on... Creeper, help me!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ここ？
Here?
Another ladder?
あ、こっちか
Ah, this way.
はい！いやー！
Okay! Nooo!
手伝って！これ！
Help me with this!
もうクリアした方がいいかも。いや、こっち行こう
Maybe I should just clear it. No, let's go this way.
こい！
Come on!
ほい
Oops.
ここか？
Is it here?
行け！
Go!
えっ？
Eh?
あ、あそこに落ちる？
Ah, do I fall down there?
いっ
Oof!
どけ！
Move!
いや、もう時間がない！
Ah, there's no more time!
おら！おら！おら！おら！
Take that! Take that!
はっ、はっ
Haa, haa
いや、やだ。やだ。
No, I don't want to! No!
いやーーー！
Noooo!
いや、これ、これじゃない！
No, this, it's not this!
なーーー！
Noooo!
We got it?
どこまー、うわ。
Where... oh.
I mean, we have nice armor now, but...
I just need shoes.
Oh yeah, what happened to the stocks? Check the stocks.
そう、いま、いま保有しているの、いま買ってるところを表示したら... 保有欄？
Yeah, right now, if you display what you hold, what you're buying... The holdings tab?
Hi.
あ、イナのボスやった。イナかと思った。
Ah, it was Ina's boss. I thought it was Ina.
おふね。
A boat.
じゃあ、ここを... How many do I have?
Then, here... How many do I have?
とりあえず、ネポラボ買うか。214か、じゃあ、200株くらい買っとくか。
First of all, should I buy NePoLaBo? 214, huh? Then, should I buy about 200 shares?
で...
And...
いや、もっと買っとくか。400...
No, maybe I should buy more. 400...
うーん、これは待つ。
Hmm, I'll wait on this one.
いや、500...
No, 500...
これは...
This one...
あ、買えた。
Ah, I bought it.
買おう。
I'll buy it.
あ、上限が300か。
Ah, is the limit 300?
あ、シカの株って、一人の上限が3000じゃなくて、みんなで3000か。
Ah, Shika's stock, is the individual limit not 3000, but 3000 for everyone?
なるほど。
I see.
Good, good, good. Okay, okay, okay. What's this? Oh...
Enhancement Part... Super Rare...
イナちゃん先輩！番長！
Ina-chan senpai! Bancho!
うわ、めっちゃ、めっちゃ装備カッコいい！ なんか...
Wow, your equipment looks so, so cool! Like...
戦ったら、これが一杯出ました。
When I fought, a bunch of these dropped.
うわ、ラッキーだ！これ、損切りはしません。
Wow, lucky! I won't cut losses on this.
え、いま、幾ら持ってるんですか？
Eh, how much money do you have right now?
いま...あ、27円。
Right now... Ah, 27 Yen.
27円！？え、貯金は？
27 Yen!? Eh, what about savings?
あ、19,000。
Ah, 19,000.
ちょっと株、株買ったから... お金がもうない。
I bought some stocks, so... I don't have any money left.
株が！？株はどうだった？マイナス75%？
Stocks!? How were the stocks? Minus 75%?
うん、あれになったのを買って、まあ、待つ。
Yeah, I bought the one that became like that, and well, I'll wait.
待つのね。待つ。
You'll wait. Wait.
上がったら、良いですね。良いですね。うん、うん。
If it goes up, that'll be good. That'd be good. Yeah, yeah.
ふふ、株で散財するタイプだったんだ、イナちゃん先輩。いや、全然。
Fufu, you were the type to squander money on stocks, Ina-chan senpai. No, not at all.
ギャンブラーだな。いや、前も、前もさ、なんか、売れると思ったら...
You're a gambler, aren't you? No, before too, like, I thought it would sell...
うん、買っていた。買っていた！
Yeah, I bought it. You bought it!
高い、高い時に買ってしまった。あ、高い時に！うん。
I ended up buying when it was high, high. Ah, when it was high! Yeah.
安い時に買わないとですね。うん。
You have to buy when it's cheap, right? Yeah.
なんか高い時に買って、安い時に売ってしまって... 株... 損してる！
Somehow buying when it's high and selling when it's cheap... Stocks... You're losing money!
株、難しいな。株、難しいな。うん。
Stocks are hard. Stocks are hard. Yeah.
え、イナちゃん先輩、この後どこ行くんですか？あ、今は、まだ決めてない。
Eh, Ina-chan senpai, where are you going after this? Ah, right now, I haven't decided yet.
ファイター、ファイター同士で、なんか、稼ぎに行きたくないですか？
As fighters, don't you want to go earn some money together?
お、い、行ってみようかな。今ちょっと、なんか、あのバトルやってみたけど、鍵が見つからなくて...
Oh, s- should we go? Just now, like, I tried the battle, but I couldn't find the key...
あ、鍵が！ 全然、迷ったことじゃなくて、鍵が見つからなくて、もう一回やってみようかなと。
Ah, the key! It wasn't that I got lost at all, but I couldn't find the key, so I was thinking of trying again.
え、じゃあ行ってみよう、ダンジョン！行く！
Eh, then let's go, to the dungeon! Let's go!
鍵見つけよう！イェーイ！ここ。
Let's find the key! Yay! Here.
ここだ。あ、ここだ。
It's here. Ah, it's here.
今度はファイターだ。ファイター！ファイター！
This time it's fighter. Fighter! Fighter!
そら先輩！
Sora-senpai!
ファイター。とらちゃん先輩もファイター？
Fighter. Is Tora-chan senpai a fighter too?
いや、お、試しにやってみようと思って。おお。
No, I- I thought I'd give it a try. Oh.
今からダンジョン行きますけど...
We're going to the dungeon now but...
一緒に行きます？
Shall we go together?
行って、行っていい？
Can I, can I go?
はい。
Yes.
あ、いぬちゃんじゃん。
Ah, it's Inu-chan.
ある、ありますか、剣とか。
Is there... do you have a sword or something?
えっとね、この、これをさっきね、拾った。
Well, I picked this up earlier.
おお、強い！
Oh, strong!
もらった、もらうちゃん。
I got it, thank you.
うん。
Yeah.
ごちゃ！
Gocha!
でもこれ、使った後ってどうやって落ちるんだろう？
But how do we exit after we're done?
えっと、Tをぽちって、スタートをクリックします。
Well, you press T and click start.
スタート。
Start.
スタート...
Start...
よっし。
Alright.
はい。
Yes.
行きましょう！
Let's go!
はい！
Yes!
あ、こんな装備で大丈夫かな？
Ah, is it okay with this kind of equipment?
大丈夫です！
It's okay!
守ります！
I'll protect you!
先輩を守れーー！
Protect Senpai!
痛い！やめてよ！やめて！
Ouch! Stop it! Stop!
パンしか来ない。
Only bread is coming.
同じところに...
In the same place...
パンは要らない。パンしか来ない。パンは要らない。
I don't need bread. Only bread is coming. I don't need bread.
あるかな？
Is there one?
何もないね。
There's nothing here.
何もない。パンしか来ない。
Nothing here. Only bread is coming.
上かな？
Is it upstairs?
あ、強化パーツガチャ！
Oh, upgrade parts gacha!
おお、ガチャガチャ。あ、落ちた。
Oh, gacha gacha. Ah, I fell.
やめてよ！やめてよ！やめてよ！
Stop it! Stop it! Stop it!
痛い！やめてよ！
Ouch! Stop it!
あれ、もうここは終わりだ。
Ah, this place is already cleared.
えっと、ここかな？
Well, is it here?
ういー。あっ！
Wheee. Ah!
え、あ、そら先輩、そら先輩！
Eh, ah, Sora-senpai, Sora-senpai!
わっ、強化パーツガチャ回したことありますか？
Wow, have you ever rolled the upgrade parts gacha?
ないよ。
No.
これ、回してみてくだ...
Try rolling this...
あれ？うい。でも右クリック？
Huh? Wheee. But right click?
あ、本みたい...
Ah, like a book...
あー！本みたいなのが出てきて...
Ah! A book-like thing came out...
ノーマルみたいなやつ？
Like a normal one?
ノーマル、何それ、それを...
Normal? What's that? Put that...
同じところかな？うわ。
Is it the same place? Whoa.
危ない！危ない！
Dangerous! Dangerous!
元々持ってる武器に、つければいいのかな？
Should I put it on the weapon I already have?
なんか、茶色い巾着みたいなやつのスロットにはめると、強くなります。
If you slot it into something like a brown pouch, it gets stronger.
あー。
Ah.
こっち、鍵あります？
Do we have a key over here?
うーん、なかったです。
Hmm, there wasn't one.
どこかな？
Where could it be?
敵いない。
No enemies.
あ, これを入れるの？
Ah, do we put this in?
あれ？どこ行っちゃったんだろう、みんな。見失っちゃった。
Huh? Where did everyone go? I lost sight of them.
これ、ランダム、ランダムかな？ドロップ。
Is this a random, random drop?
上に参りましょう。
Let's go upstairs.
鍵を探してみましょう。
Let's look for the key.
あ、モンスターから、モンスターから出るっぽい？かも。
Ah, does it seem to drop from monsters? Maybe.
え、ここなんか部屋？
Eh, is this a room?
お、何？ここどこ？え？
Oh, what? Where is this? Eh?
あ、なんか壁に...
Ah, on the wall...
下に行ける場所があって...え？何もないけど。
There's a place to go down... eh? There's nothing though.
何かが、あると思った。
I thought there was something.
いっぱいいる！いっぱいいる！あー！
There are so many! There are so many! Ah!
あ、ごめん！大丈夫です！おし。
Ah, sorry! It's okay! Alright.
うーん...
Hmm...
あ、なんかこれ...
Ah, this is...
あ、パンだった。
Ah, it was bread.
パン。
Bread.
パンしかない。
Only bread.
ここにも、入れる。
We can go in here too.
あ, 鍵！
Ah, key!
あった？
Did you find it?
あっ、あ、これ、これ漢字読めない。鍵、鍵ですよね？
Ah, ah, I can't read this Kanji. It's a key, it's a key, right?
漢字読めないんですけど、多分これ鍵、だと思います。
I can't read the Kanji, but I think this is a key.
鍵なら...
If it's a key...
マークが違ければ、きっと鍵だよ。
If the icon is different, it's definitely a key.
あ、鍵だー！
Ah, it's a key!
鍵だー！イェーイ！
Key! Yay!
これ、イェーイ！
This, yay!
えっ、なんかボス、ボスが！
Eh, there's a boss, a boss!
ボス、ボス、ボス。え, 何これ？
Boss, boss, boss. Eh, what is this?
おら、おら、おら、おら。
Take this! Take this!
おっち、おっち、おっち。
Take this, take this, take this!
おっち、おっち。
Take this, take this!
え、でも倒せそう、これ。
Eh, but we can beat this.
えい、えい、えい、えい。
Ei, ei, ei, ei.
あ、危ない！パンを！
Ah, dangerous! The bread!
うりゃー！
Uryah!
おっち、おっち。
Take this, take this!
あちっ、おっち、おっち、おっち。
Hot! Take this, take this, take this!
熱い！熱い！熱い！
Hot! Hot! Hot!
おっち、おっち。
Take this, take this!
イェーイ！できた！やったー！これやー！イェーイ！
Yay! We did it! Yay! This is it! Yay!
おお！ お金いっぱい！
Oh! There's lots of money!
あ、ネザライトが
Ah, netherite is...
ネザライトがある！
There is netherite!
もう一個あるよ、ネザライト
There's one more netherite!
ネザライトどうぞどうぞ
Please, go ahead and take the netherite.
あ、とってください
Ah, please take it.
イェーイ！ もらったよ、ネザライト！
Yay! I got the netherite!
じゃ、ガチャガチャもらいましょう
Then let's get the gacha-gacha.
ガチャ？ ガチャ。
Gacha? Gacha.
強化パーツ スーパーレア
Enhancement part: Super Rare!
あ、スーパーレアだ！ お、レア。
Ah, it's a Super Rare! Oh, a rare one.
おおー。ファイターもよさそうだな。
Ooh. Fighter seems pretty good too.
強いですね、ファイター
Fighter is strong, isn't it?
いやー、楽しい
Wow, this is fun!
えー、もう一回行きたいかも
Eh... I might want to go again.
一緒に行こう？
Shall we go together?
うん、行きましょう
Yeah, let's go.
あ、なんか動けなくなっちゃった、上手く
Ah, somehow I can't move properly.
お？
Oh?
あ、日本語表記になってる
Ah, it changed to Japanese display.
クリック、お！
Click... oh!
おおー！
Ooh!
楽しい。戻ってきた。
So fun. We're back.
強化パーツ、レア。あ、またもらってる
Enhancement part: Rare. Ah, I got another one.
こおぉぉぉぉん！ え？
Kooooon! Eh?
なんか今...
Just now, something...
こんって言った？
Did she say 'kon'?
もう一回行く？
Are we going again?
もう一回行きましょう
Let's go again!
でも、そら先輩、今お金めっちゃ入ったんじゃないですか？
But Sora-senpai, didn't you get a lot of money just now?
うん
Yeah.
あ、なんかATMに...
Ah, maybe in the ATM...
ATMに入れといたほうがいいかも
It might be better to deposit it into the ATM.
ATM？ あ、ここ、ここです
ATM? Ah, here, it's here.
ここに
Over here.
こうだ
Like this.
へえ、いいじゃん
Wow, that's nice.
めっちゃいいじゃん
That's really nice.
売ってる？
Are you selling?
売ってます。絶対いらないだろ、これ。
I'm selling them. Nobody is going to need this.
これここにいれとこう
Let's put this in here.
1円で2個売ろう
I'll sell two for 1 yen.
マウントとろうと思ったのに、普通に教えてあげちゃった
I wanted to brag about it, but I just told her normally.
そうだよ、マウントとれてないよ
Exactly, you didn't get to brag at all.
マウント空振りだ、これ
My attempt to brag was a total miss.
よかった
Good.
何、何？ 何行くの？
What, what? Where are we going?
行きましょう
Let's go.
これ、ハチミツはどうするの？
What do we do with this honey?
アーマーよりファイターのほうがこれ...
Rather than Armor, Fighter might be...
便利なのかもしれない。そうですね。
...more convenient. That's true.
あ、自分一人でも行こうと思えばいけるんだ、しかも
Ah, and actually, you can go alone if you wanted to.
行こう、行こう
Let's go, let's go!
うわ！ クリーパーだらけだ！
Whoa! It's full of creepers!
爆発ばっかりや
Nothing but explosions!
いやー！
Nooo!
クリーパーだらけはまずいな<
A place full of creepers is bad news.
お、鍵！
Oh, the key!
え、もう？ もうありました。
Eh, already? We already found it.
早い！ いや、でもなんか...
So fast! No, but somehow...
見ましょうか、チェスト。あ、チェストとか見て。
Shall we check the chests? Ah, let's check the chests...
いいものがあったら。パン。
If there's anything good. Bread.
パン、パン、パン。パン。
Bread, bread, bread. Bread.
パン、パン、パン
Bread, bread, bread.
あれ？ いや、みてください。
Huh? No, look at this.
開けられなくなっちゃった。パンかね？
I can't open it anymore. Is it bread?
パンしかねえのか、この国は
Does this country only have bread?
なんだ？ 開けれなくなっちゃったな
What's wrong? I can't open it anymore.
ああ、こうしてると必殺技が...
Ah, if I do this, the special move...
パン、パン、パン、パン、パン、パン、パン
Bread, bread, bread, bread, bread, bread, bread...
パン、パン。おーい。
Bread, bread. Hellooo.
ダイヤ！
Diamonds!
いや、これって
No, this is...
ピカピカしてんのいいの、冒険って
Adventure is so nice with shiny things.
何のための冒険だったか
What was the adventure even for?
こんなに
So much of this...
早くもらえるけど
We can get them fast, but...
チョコ食べよう
Let's eat some chocolate.
狙われちゃう
I'm being targeted!
大丈夫ですか？ 大丈夫！
Are you okay? I'm okay!
ネザライトになったから、ちょっと強くなった
Since I got netherite, I became a bit stronger.
そろそろ行きますか？
Shall we head out soon?
行きましょう
Let's go.
じゃ、ここだっちゃ
Then, it's here.
鍵を、ほい
Key... there!
お、また変異ブリーズか
Oh, mutated Breeze again?
行きます
Here I go!
もう燃えとる
It's already burning!
え、ちょっ、ちょっ、ちょっ、やっ！
Eh, wait, wait, wait... Yah!
えいっ！
Take that!
あつい、あつい！
Hot, hot!
あついあついあついあついあつい！
It's so hot, hot, hot, hot, hot!
むちゃくちゃ、食べよう。食べよう。
This is crazy! Let's eat, let's eat.
うわあ！
Whoa!
これ交代タイミング悪い。
Our rotation timing is bad.
おい、おい、おい、おい、おい。
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
あっち、あっち。
Hot, hot.
あー！
Ah!
シールドがなくなった。
My shield is gone.
もうちょっと、もうちょっと。
Just a little more, just a little more.
あっち、あっち。
Hot, hot.
あっちい。
So hot!
お行儀が悪いですね。
It has bad manners.
いぇーい！
Yay!
あ、でも今回は一万か。
Oh, but this time it's only 10,000.
あ、最初、初めてやると。あー、なるほどなるほど。
Ah, when you do it for the first time... Ah, I see, I see.
二回目以降は一万円なの。
From the second time onwards, it's 10,000 yen.
ダイヤ入ってるよ。
There's a diamond in here.
ヘルメット。
A helmet.
そらちゃん、ネザライトのヘルメット。
Sora-chan, a Netherite Helmet.
お、あるよ。
Oh, there is one.
いいんですか？いただきます。
Is it okay? Thank you!
ネザライト1個。
One Netherite.
おー、強い。
Oh, strong.
あははは！ じゃあ…
Ahahaha! Alright...
うー。
Uh...
"Can you tame bees from beehives? Placing honey in beehive will yield one bee..."
"...about 10 minutes." うー。
"...about 10 minutes." Uh...
お、アスレチック。
Oh, parkour.
"Shear farmer job... breed and hatchery..."
"...can you breed..."
"...beehives and hatchery... hoppers can be placed between beehives and hatchery."
これが気になるんですよね。
I'm curious about this.
うー。
Ooh...
いくらだったっけ？
How much was it again?
ファーマー、ここって…
Farmer, is this place...
これかな？あ！
Is it this? Ah!
人いる？
Is someone there?
ファーマーか。
A farmer?
Apiary... apiaryって何？
Apiary... what's an apiary?
これか？これ…ここから出る？
Is it this? Will... will they come out of here?
ちょっとあれするか。
Maybe I'll do a bit of that.
I do have 100k. So this is where the bee comes from?
待遇、就職します。
I'll take a job with good benefits.
One bee... 待遇良好。
One bee... Excellent benefits.
それ、ホッパーじゃなくていいんだ？
So we don't need a hopper for that?
待遇良好。
Excellent benefits.
さ…ハチのやつ…
The... the bee thing...
ま、でもいっぱい買ったら一気に効率が上がる的な感じなのかな。
But I guess if you buy a lot, it boosts efficiency all at once, something like that?
良好な… 一度の交配でより多くのハチが誕生する。
Good... More bees will hatch in one breeding session.
Oh, I think this is the breeding, and the actual beehive is the hive container. From the pictures.
アルケミストになりや。
You've become an Alchemist.
ね、ね、ね、ハチやった？
Hey, hey, hey, did you do bees?
え、まだやってない。
No, I haven't done it yet.
やってるでしょ、その声。やってるよね？
You are doing it, right? With that voice. You're doing it, right?
やってるよね、ハチ？ハチやってるよね？ハチやってるよね？
You're doing it, right, bees? You're doing bees, right? You're doing bees, right?
やってない、やってない。 ハチどう？ハチどう、どう、どう？ハチどうなの？
No I'm not, no I'm not. How are the bees? How are they? How are they doing?
いや、ちなみにまだマジでわからん。 え、ハチやってるでしょ、みこち。
Well, by the way, I seriously still don't understand them. Eh, you are doing bees, right, Mikochi?
やって…いや、まだわからん。え、どうなの実際？
No... No, I still don't understand. Eh, how is it actually?
いやいや、やめてよ。なんか「仲良いからみこちゃんの声わかりますよ」みたいのやめてもらっていいですか？
No, no, stop it. Can you stop doing that "we're close so I can recognize Mikochi's voice" thing?
いやいやいや、そんなのさ…いやいやみこち、だってスイカした仲じゃん、一緒に。
No, no, no, that's... No, no, Mikochi, we became close through Suika Game, together!
どうなの？正直。正直どうなん？
How is it? Honestly. Honestly, how is it?
え、ちなみにガチで、ガチで本当にまだみこちゃん走り出しだから。
Uh, by the way, seriously, seriously, Mikochi is just starting out.
あ、そうなんだ。 うん。
Ah, is that so. Yeah.
いや、イナはわかると思う。やってみる。
Yeah, I think I get it. Let's try it.
やってみる。
Let's try it.
これを買って…
Buy this...
え、ファイターでさ、今さ…
Eh, in fighter, right now...
あ…
Ah...
これを買って…
Buy this and...
家に帰る。
Go back home.
ね？
Right?
あ、ハチミツも買わないと。忘れた。
Ah, I have to buy honey too. I forgot.
これ、なんか家に…戻って…
So, like, go back home...
みこちゃん、謎解きやった？
Miko-chan, did you do the riddle?
やきましたよ。
I did it.
あ、もうクリアしちゃったっけ？一日一回だもんね。
Ah, you already cleared it? Since it's once a day.
でもなんか、あれは何回行っても大丈夫だけどね、って感じ。
But apparently you can go as many times as you want, kind of.
あ、なんか、一日一回になったらしい。
Ah, apparently it became once a day.
そうなんですか？一日一回になったんだ。
Is that so? It became once a day.
え、そんなことないかな？
Eh, maybe that's not the case?
あれ？さっきめちゃ行ってたから。
Huh? Because I went a lot earlier.
で、なんか、家に戻って、お寿司以外全部買って、家に戻って、あ、お寿司忘れたって。
And, like, go back home, buy everything except sushi, go back home, and then go, "Ah, I forgot the sushi."
うー、そのパターン...
Ooh, that pattern...
ほい。
There.
へい、へい、へい、へい。
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
で、これを...
So, this...
どこ？ その、おー...
where? Um... oh...
ここかな？
Maybe here?
で、
And...
ここ、これを入れる？
here, do I put this in?
いや、これじゃないか？
No, is it not this?
これなのか？
Is it this one?
なんか10分、で...
Apparently, in 10 minutes...
出るって。
it'll come out.
10分、これから10分。
10 minutes, 10 minutes from now.
これから10分、待つ。
I'll wait 10 minutes from now.
待って、何も起こらなかったら...
I'll wait, and if nothing happens...
聞く。
I'll ask.
それだけ。
That's it.
うん、10分待ったら...
Yeah, it says if I wait 10 minutes...
出るって。
it'll come out.
書いてる。
That's what it says.
だから、ちょっと待つ。
So, I'll wait a bit.
いやいやいや、そうそうそう。
No, no, no, yeah, yeah, yeah.
見えるんでしょ？ このプログレスのバーが。
You can see this progress bar, right?
そうそうそう。
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
ね、ね、ね、ね？ ね？
Right, right, right? Right?
そうだよ。
Exactly.
そうですね、ここから。じゃあ。
Let's see... here. Then...
えっと、もっと...
Um, let's do...
ファーミングしましょう。
more farming.
ここ木、全部無くなったらいいかも。
It might be good if all the trees here are gone.
いや、ちょっとダイヤの これ持っていこう、買うに行こうかな。
Actually, maybe I'll go buy... should I bring this diamond?
Carrots is 200, wheat is 400?
Oh, wheat meta?
Wheat meta?
Okay, after this axe breaks we can go...
and buy a new axe.
ジングルベル、ジングルベル、ジングルベル...
Jingle bell, jingle bell, jingle bell...
これサンタ？
Is this Santa?
サンタクロース、イエス！
Santa Claus, yes!
サンタ！
Santa!
プレゼントは？サンタ！
Where's my present, Santa?
サンタ、プレゼントは？
Santa, where's my present?
プレ、プレ...
Pre-, pre-...
プレゼント！サンタありがとう！
A present! Thank you, Santa!
えーとじゃあ、えーとじゃあ。
Well then, well then...
プレゼントね。
Here's your present.
ここら辺あげるか、ここら辺。
I'll give you something from around here.
プレゼント、ふたつ！
Two presents!
プレゼント！いぇーい！
Presents! Yay!
ふたつ。
Two!
使ってるのじゃダメか。
Ah, using it doesn't work?
あ、返ってきた。うん、じゃあこれあげようかな。
Ah, it came back. Well, I'll give you this.
はい。
Here.
ステーキ！
Steak!
ホウ、ホウ、ホウ！
Ho, ho, ho!
サンタ！
Santa!
Santa is real!
ステーキもらったぜ、ステーキ。
I got steak! Steak!
いや、ちょうどこれ必要だったな。
Actually, I really needed this.
さすがサンタ。
As expected of Santa.
私が何を欲しがってるか分かってる。
She knows exactly what I want.
サンタは...
Santa...
サンタはいるんだ。
Santa is real.
そっちをきな、すてーき
Cut that one down, steak-y...
すてーき
...steak-y...
あ、りんご
Ah, an apple.
あー
Ah...
りんご
An apple.
え？
Eh?
えー、なるほど？
Eh, I see?
へえー
Huh...
So, we do have two slots.
I was like, why do I have more HP? We do have two slots unlocked. I can't use this slot.
But, I still have two slots I can use, and I have all the bees.
なるほど、Iわかる。
I see, I understand.
Iわかる。
I understand.
So, you can still have some of it equipped.
えい、えい。
Hup, hup.
Okay, let me just do this...
this, this...
this, this.
ステーキ、食べれない。
Steak, I can't eat it.
おなか、いや お腹空いたけど、お腹空いてない。
My stomach... wait, I'm hungry, but I'm not hungry.
から食べれない。
So I can't eat it.
Eh, blaze rod? Where did I get the blaze rod?
いや、もう一つ必要かもな。
Wait, maybe I need one more.
いいね。
Nice.
こう、どこがいいか。ここがいいか。
Like this... where would be good? Here?
じゃ、うーん、どうしよう。食べもの、上に？
Well, hmm, what should I do? Put the food on top?
これは必要。
This is necessary.
だね。
Right.
あっ、キャロットも。
Ah, carrots too.
え？なんか、なんていう？こう...
Eh? Like, what's it called? Like this...
みっつ。
Three.
Plus two more... ah, two more honey. Yeah, we should have time.
We should hatch all the, uh, bees,
We should hatch all the... bees,
and then we start...
breeding them for better skills and stuff, is what I think we're supposed to do.
Pretty sure.
Or like, keep getting more bees and then also breed them as well.
ほう、なんだ？
Huh, what's this?
なるほど、なるほど。じゃ、いれとこう。
I see, I see. Then I'll put it in.
うーん。
Hmm...
And then once we...
uh, whatchamacallit, once we...
get more bees, I think we can start breeding them, and still get more bees, and then we just try to find the one with the best skills, I think.
I think that's the play.
Okay, I do have bucket.
Okay, I do have a bucket.
I think my plan is going to work. Tomorrow, I will fish and also, you know,
get my farm going.
Ah, do I just want to make this entire field...
Oh, I forgot to buy... oh, I guess I have the shovel.
I'm just gonna flatten this area out.
Um, yeah, one more hour, one hour 15 minutes.
But I think that will be a pretty good system if I wanna...
...if I wanna farm and...
...fish?
And since the growth of the farming stuff is...
...pretty fast...
...we should be able to...
...get quite a lot.
Does sugarcane give you any money? Good question.
Nope.
Maybe crafting something with sugarcane would?
Does it? Hold on.
Was it 73?
No.
Hey, at least I can make some cake.
Maybe.
Or maybe I can sell the cakes.
Actually, cakes are not that great because they're not as portable.
Ah! You know what I should do? I should go to the Nether just to get netherite so I can make a netherite hoe.
Because that's what a true farmer would do.
Maybe I should make it a goal... Maybe I should just commission... I should buy a netherite...
...from someone who actually goes in the Nether.
All right, I think this is a pretty big farm.
Eisho.
Eish.
Okay, that's a pretty big land, isn't it?
A solid foundation for a farm.
Wait, is this sand?
Ah!
All right.
How should I go about doing this?
Ah!
I miss Sir Meow.
Sir Meow...
Oh! We got a bee!
What skill does it have?
Can I equip it? Do I have to equip it? How do I... how do I use it? Do I have to use it?
Is it?
I'm trying.
Hold on, let me read.
Uh... I should be able to... use it?
Need the apiary? I do? Oh...
イナ！
Ina!
はい！
Hi!
イナハウス？
Ina's house?
イナハウス、ここ。
Ina's house is here.
おお、いいね。
Oh, nice.
うんと、地下、地下。
Hmm, underground, underground.
Ina, Ina house.
Ina, Ina house... Hold on, let me get this first.
大丈夫、大丈夫。
It's fine, it's fine.
I should make an iron hoe though, so it lasts a little longer.
Where did I leave the iron? Oh, it's in my...
My inventory is a mess. Ah... why do I have three...
...diamond swords?
And a wooden... I mean, I can keep the wooden axe.
Hold...
There we go.
Eh?
Is this it?
はい。
Okay.
And...
Uh...
水、水、ほい。水、水、ほい。
Water, water, here. Water, water, here.
And then I can do carrots for this.
Actually, maybe I can buy different seeds...
...from the shop.
Yeah.
Some cash crop...
I can sell some of the crops, right? I think.
Pumpkins...
Place the bee into the ground?
No...
あっ、戻りなさい！
Ah, go back!
あっ、あっ！
Ah, ah!
Oh, almost another one.
I know we can do four around, but it looks nicer this way, doesn't it?
It's calculated, guys, it's calculated... It's not.
Well, that's calculated.
Trust, trust.
Let me go...
...get seeds.
Look at all those pumpkins!
Ooh, a row of water and pumpkins.
よいしょ、よいしょ。
Heave-ho, heave-ho.
え、でも消耗しちゃうよ。
Eh, but it gets consumed.
D-Yenとかで売れるんだ。
It sells for D-Yen or something.
おっけー。
Okay.
養蜂箱ないと、でも意味ないのでは？
But wouldn't it be useless without a beehive?
Pumpkin...
ハチミツがなくなっちゃうね。
The honey will run out.
Twenty.
So, we might need this...
...but I thought this was only for breeding the bees.
おっけーおっけー。おじさん、3000了解。
Okay, okay. Mister, 3000, got it.
Don don don don don...
もぐもぐ。
Nom nom.
Oh.
We need pumpkin...
You need to breed them to get the one with special skills?
Hoh hoh hoh.
Hoh hoh hoh hoh.
Yeah, これを...
Yeah, this...
水があるからできないかな。
Since there's water, maybe I can't do it.
これをさ... うーん、どうしよう。
With this... hm, what should I do?
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, ten.
Hehehe.
Tactical fishing.
Okay, okay, okay.
10。
10.
で...
And...
あ、もう...
Ah, jeez...
Bee in hand looks silly?
It's fine.
Ah! Zombie!
この時を待っていた！
I've been waiting for this moment!
Yay! Monster Hunter!
Free money!
You know, how about I go, one, two, three, four... four more here, so it looks nice.
Oh, wait. What am I doing?
I need to do this.
And then I'll go get a bunch more.
Now... Well, they are growing.
Do I need one more... row?
Like this?
Oh, why is there suddenly...
Ah! My farm!
You ruined my farm!
My carrots!
Like this, and then the pumpkins will grow.
Sorry, I was never really... a pumpkin farmer.
And then I would need two this way if I go like this.
Okay, okay. I wakaru.
Okay, okay. I understand.
Right, right, right?
So then I would place one here...
...and then it'll grow this way.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14.
No need to till for pumpkins? But I want to.
It just... It just feels nice, you know?
The pumpkins! They're growing! They're growing!
Oh no, everything is falling in price.
Oh!
It's time to buy, buy, buy!
Oh, oops.
I meant to...
...I meant to do this.
What am I going to do with all these carrots?
Oh, this is time to buy NeFoLaBo.
Okay, that's good.
Make another double chest for all the food.
Any more wood?
Is that enough?
Yes. Okay.
I shall put the food chest up top.
Never mind, I forgot!
I forgot. You can't open chests like that.
The ceiling. Ah, the ceiling.
Okay.
Oh, right. I forgot about this field.
All right. Maybe we can, maybe we can buy...
Oh, more bees should be done.
Maybe we'll be able to buy the thing to test it.
I mean, I would need it anyways.
So, I want to test it that way.
I could sell... None of them really rose, huh?
None of the stonks really rose.
Creeper... They do spawn after all.
Just want to make sure I don't ruin anyone's...
シールド持ってないや。ま、いっか。
I don't have a shield. Oh well, whatever.
Ooh, they're glowing.
Buy the stonks first.
Maybe remove this first?
No, like, these two slots are open by default.
Yeah, maybe spawns are turned on now.
Stonks.
Yes, yes, yes.
ってか、みんな買ってそうだよね。
I mean, everyone seems to have bought some, right?
どう計算したか聞いても...
Even if we ask how they calculated it...
え、取引...
Huh, trading...
てかもう全部買ってもいいんだよ。
Actually, we can just buy all of them.
あれ？株買いました？
Wait, did you buy stocks?
買ってる、今。
I'm buying right now.
お、どれぐらい買うんですか？
Oh, how much are you buying?
Oh, should I buy everything?
え、マイナスやん！ちょっと待って...
Wait, it's negative! Hold on...
13... 13円だよ。
13... It's 13 yen.
え？ネポラボめっちゃ安い。13円だ。
What? NePoLaBo is super cheap. It's 13 yen.
I'll buy.
ぶっぱ、ぶっぱ。
Dump it all, dump it all.
え、今買うべきじゃない？じゃあ。
Wait, shouldn't we buy right now then?
そうだね。
Yeah.
上がるかわかんないけど、お言葉を信ず...
We don't know if it'll go up, but I'll believe...
Is it going to go up?
え、今のうちに買っとこう。
Let's buy while we can.
えっと、優待もらえる...
Let's see, we get benefits...
どうやって貰うんだそれ？
How do we get that?
確かに、どうやって貰ったらいいの？
True, how should we get it?
2000ぐらい買ったらいい？マックス？
Should we buy about 2000? Max?
Go.
どるけんが26。
Doroken is 26.
Oh, hmm.
あ、2000個まで貰える...
Ah, we can get up to 2000...
1日の取引上限に達した。何だって？
Reached daily trade limit. What did you say?
2000の、あ、2万6000円もかかる。
2000, ah, it costs 26,000 yen.
Aww.
2万、買ったら勝手に貰えるよ。
20,000, if you buy it you'll get it automatically.
あ、購入制限あるんだ。殆ど、殆ど。
Ah, there's a purchase limit. Almost, almost.
Ah, Shishiro Foods?
I can sell...
...but I just can't buy anymore.
1900...
1900。
1900.
NePoLaBo.
It is what it is.
Daijoubu.
It's okay.
90...
Uh, what was I gonna do?
All right. Event. Athletic. Mini-game.
Eh?
Heh...
This...
俺、株でもひと稼ぎするわ。
I'm gonna make a fortune with stocks too.
えっと、お引き出し、マックス。
Let's see, withdraw... max.
よし！
Alright!
Yeah, I was gonna save money.
メッチャお腹空いた。
I'm so hungry.
Oh, I'm so hungry.
Buy...
そうだね、一旦アルケミストでいいような気がするな。
Yeah, I feel like Alchemist is fine for now.
How do I sell?
Oh, hunger.
I'm so hungry, I can't think of anything.
おいしいね。
Tastes good.
Ah, not that.
Honey Bottle... 100...
thousand...
15 minutes... hmm...
No, I shouldn't eat, I need to sleep after this, you know?
いや、このクリーパーめっちゃヤバいじゃん。
Wait, this creeper is super dangerous.
いやああ！
Noooo!
いや、でもネザライトだから大丈夫か。
Well, but I have Netherite, so it's fine, right?
いや、でも怖い。
But it's still scary.
だれの家壊さないようにしないと...
I need to make sure I don't blow up anyone's house...
よし。
Alright.
まあ、ネザライトですからね、大丈夫だよ。
Well, since it's Netherite, I'll be fine.
Oh right, I was gonna buy pumpkin seeds.
えっと、14マイナス5、9... 9。
Let's see, 14 minus 5 is 9... 9.
いや、ラーメンか。でもラーメン食べ...食べたら良くないよ、この時間に。
Wait, ramen? But if I eat ramen... eating ramen at this hour is not good.
ですね。食べちゃダメなんです。
Right. I shouldn't eat.
ケミスト強いんだよ。
Chemist is really strong.
あ、強いですね！
Oh, it is strong!
ししろん！ししろん！
Shishiron! Shishiron!
はい、はい、はい、はい。
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
これどう使うんですか？
How do you use this?
それはね...
Well, that is...
そ... あ、こっち来てもらっていい？
So... ah, can you come over here?
へええ。
Huh...
装備スロットっていう、装備の... この茶色いのを開いてもらうと...
If you open the equipment slot... this brown one...
ハチを装備できるスロットが中段、真ん中にあるんで、そこにセットしてもらいたい。
There's a slot in the middle row where you can equip bees, so I want you to put it there.
セットができない。
I can't put it in.
あ、じゃあ多分ノーマルの何の能力もないハチだから...
Ah, then it's probably a normal bee with no abilities...
あ！
Ah!
なるほど。
I see.
そう、まず養蜂箱でハチ同士を掛け合わせて...
Right, first, breed bees together in the beehive...
うん。
Yeah.
あの、ちょっと能力ついたハチ... 良くなったら、これに装備できるようになる。
And once you get a bee with some abilities... a better one, you'll be able to equip it.
あ、なるほどなるほど。
Ah, I see, I see.
うんうん。
Yeah, yeah.
はい、はい、はい、はい。ありがとうございます。
Yes, yes, yes. Thank you very much!
はい、おっけー。
Alright, okay.
はい。
Okay.
Oh, so it's gacha.
あ、パン作ってくるの忘れた。
Ah, I forgot to make bread.
じゃあ、ちょっと後でやらなきゃ。
Well, I'll have to do it later.
So you want to keep making bees and breeding them until you get ones with the ability, and then you can equip it.
Thank you, Shishiron!
なるほど...
I see...
ガチャですね...
It's gacha...
いや、ガチャですね。
Yeah, it's gacha.
来ると思いましたよ。
I knew this was coming.
あ...
Ah...
No, don't grow that way. Stop.
There we go. お、早い。
There we go. Oh, fast.
あーん。
Ah...
いいですね。
Nice.
And then okay, so if I put that, that, two-two...
If I do this...
ね、ね、ね？
Right, right, right?
で、それで、それで、それで...
And then, and then...
これを...
This...
こうしたら...
If I do this...
そして、そして、そして...
And then, and then...
あ、ここか。
Ah, here.
ね、ね、ね、ね...
Hey, hey, hey, hey...
Ah, I don't have a shovel. I'm too lazy.
Forgive me.
It's okay, I will fence them in a bit.
んで？んで？
And? And?
で、で、で、で、で...
And, and, and, and, and...
で...
And...
あ、待った。
Oh, wait.
こ、こっちじゃないよ。
Th-This isn't the way.
戻って。
Go back.
そうだよ。
That's it.
でもなんかさ、気のせいかもしれないけど、ここの...
But you know, maybe it's just my imagination, but over here...
か... か... かぼ... かぼじゃない。
pu... pu... pump... not pumpkin.
After getting the one here, like, it immediately grows here.
So I'm wondering if it's like a...
...like a thing. Hmm.
かぼちゃ。
Pumpkin.
A glitch?
ふーん... ふーん...
Hmm... Hmm...
Maybe just lucky?
Or...
How's that?
Not bad, not bad.
All right, maybe I should just place...
That's a lot of pumpkins.
Actually, now that...
I want my plants to grow in the dark.
ね、ね？やってみる。
Right, right? I'll try it.
Ah, previous was just lucky.
Maybe I should fence off the area.
えい。
Take this!
I was just lucky last time.
えー、また？
Eh, again?
Ah, give me a trident! Give me, give me!
No, my farm!
I'm gonna need to light up the area now.
あ、クリーパーか。
Ah, a creeper...
Shoot...
いや、多いよね。
Man, there's a lot of them.
特にここ。
Especially here.
Ah...
これぐらいならいいかな。
I guess this is enough...
Oh, bones.
I'll accept bones.
Can get bone meal for even faster growth.
No, my farm!
How dare you!
Well, I didn't light it up enough, I guess.
My farm!
Oh, no...
いや、のど渇かない。
No, I'm not thirsty.
Ah...
Maybe we will make it a goal tomorrow to reach 100k.
And then buy the other thing.
I mean, I could, but then we can only respec once tomorrow.
You know what, I'm gonna make...
...a box.
Oh, I don't have enough.
Hum hum hum...
What was I gonna do?
It's alright, okay.
Yeah, I was gonna make a chest once, mind.
Fences can wait.
Osh.
Alright, wood, wood, wood, wood, wood.
Wood wood?
いや、モンハンまたやりたいな。
Man, I want to play Monster Hunter again.
久しぶりに。
It's been a while.
Genius na...
Genius idea...
...not genius idea, okay.
Just put it here.
Alright, oh, I forgot to put all this honey in.
Aha aha aha...
Can we do anything with the pumpkin? Can we sell it?
Wood, wood.
ん？
Hm?
あー、だから...
Ah, that's why...
I was wondering why I had one random pumpkin seed, and it seems like...
...that one seed broke, or the... thing broke.
あー！
Ah!
やめて。
Stop it.
ここダメだからね。
Don't grow here, okay?
はい。
Okay.
パンプ-... あ！
Pump-... ah!
Pumpkins really do grow fast.
Like, I don't even have time to fish.
あ...
Ah...
No! No! そんなバナナ！
No! No! No way!
Where's that one pumpkin seed? There we go.
そ-... そんなバナナ...
N-... No way...
そろそろ時間がないのだと？
Are you saying I'm running out of time?
どこだっけ？
Where was it?
ここですよね。はい。
It's here, right? Okay.
そんなバナナ...
No way...
No automation is allowed...
...on the server.
It would make things too easy.
Oh! I keep placing it in the wrong spot.
No, it is the right spot. No, yeah, yeah. Okay.
There we go.
I'm so bad at this.
こっちだよね？
This way, right?
あ、こっちか。
Ah, this way?
こっち。
This way.
ね？え？合ってる？
Right? Eh? Is it right?
ここ？
Here?
な？
Right?
Wait, we already have 33K. Wow!
Okay, I think...
Hoo, I mean there, there has been progress, which is good.
I just don't know what to do with everything.
I should make one more...
お！30分！
Oh! 30 minutes!
Right, so I... I will need...
to breed, for sure.
Which means I can get three more bees.
Although I technically only need two right now.
I'm getting pretty close.
I have what? 70... 80...
84k?
Let's see. I wonder if there is anything we can sell.
We shall...
No, sugarcane doesn't give money.
カブ買っとこ、うわ。
I'll buy some turnips, whoa.
よし...
Alright...
おー。
Oh.
あと、もうちょっとだな。
Just a little bit more.
Ah! I can sell pumpkin pie!
Oh! I can sell bees!
Oh, Combat Support Bee.
Ah...
I can sell pumpkin pie. How do you make pumpkin pie?
I can sell the carrots and wheat. Wait, don't you need wheat to make pumpkin pie?
I can definitely sell carrots though.
Wait, you know what? I'm gonna make an investment.
I'm gonna get a shulker box because it's 30k, which will allow me to carry...
oh, everything.
キー、もうちょっと行く？
Kee, should we go a bit more?
Carry all the carrots and sell it. It's an investment.
マックス、マックス。
Max, max.
And hopefully it'll get me something.
That way I can sell a lot more things at once. Mwahahaha.
Automation is not allowed from what I know.
Alright.
We shall move all the carrots.
That's nice, actually.
Let me bring all the carrots from there.
I think we can place a hopper...
underneath the bee thing, but not anywhere else? I'm not sure, we'll see.
Have the carrots grown?
There's still a few that still need growing.
We'll get the pumpkin- ah.
We'll at least get the pumpkin while we're here.
My slow life plan is coming true.
Ah!
My axe...
I need to learn how to make pumpkin pie.
Pumpkin, sugar, egg. I need chickens!
Sugar we have plenty of.
We should start harvesting these actually, for the sugar.
Need to catch some... some chickens out there.
Is it profitable to buy eggs for pumpkin pie? Do they sell eggs? That would change things.
Okay, the carrots are ready.
Eggs sell 50? Actually, it's still profitable to buy eggs, huh?
Cuz pumpkin pie sells for 300 each. And I grow the sugarcane and pumpkin.
And I can raise chickens and... just buy and profit.
We have the best of both worlds.
この声は...サンタ？
This voice... Santa?
ホウ ホウ ホウ！
Ho, ho, ho!
サンター！
Santa!
ホウ ホウ ホウ ホウ！
Ho, ho, ho, ho!
いや、クリスマスは早いね。
Wow, Christmas is early, isn't it?
うん、でも、プレゼントはないんだよ。
Yeah, but there are no presents.
ええ？いな、悪い子？
Eh? Is Ina a bad girl?
いい子だね。
You're a good girl.
いい子はプレゼント...
Good girls get presents...
これあれか。これ、さ、これ...
Is this that? This, you know, this...
あなたが落としたのは、右のコロネスキーですか？
Is the one you dropped the right Koronesuki?
いいえ。
No.
左のコロネスキーですか？
Is it the left Koronesuki?
いいえ。
No.
どっちも私のコロネスキーじゃないです。
Neither of them are my Koronesuki.
違うんですね？
They are not, right?
違うんです。
They are not.
うーん、正直な良い子には、コロネスキーをあげましょう！
Hmm, to an honest good girl, I shall give you Koronesuki!
ホウ ホウ ホウ！
Ho, ho, ho!
きた！
Here they are!
A bee.
Okay. Now that's six bees, and no way to breed them.
I wonder how... how long it takes to breed them actually. Let's see.
Uh, every 30 minutes.
So, it's important that I actually do this pretty early tomorrow.
いや、マスコットか。
Wait, they're mascots?
あ、入らん。使えない。ここか。
Ah, won't fit. Can't use it. Here?
あ、間違えた。うーん、うーん、ほい。
Ah, made a mistake. Hmm, hmm, hop.
おけ、おけ、おけ。
Ok, ok, ok.
タコトモも多分いるよ。
There are probably Takodachis too.
ええと...
Let's see...
22?
I don't think they sell eggs.
It's like, um...
It's more of a... they buy eggs.
So we will have to go out into the field and get some eggs to hatch.
Wait, do I got carrot crops on me?
Oh, my... melon slice...
What else can I sell?
Cake.
What do I need for cake?
Oh, I left it over there.
My crafting table...
Oh, still, egg, flour, sugar?
I need to go get chicken ASAP. Oh.
たまご、たまごが欲しい。
Eggs, I want eggs.
いや、もうすぐ帰ると思うけどさー。
Well, I think they'll return soon, but...
Maybe I should sell the wheat too, cuz it's also 20.
I think if I sell all the wheat and carrots, maybe...
...we can afford it right now?
食べないで！
Don't eat it!
あ、いや、食べてもいいか。
Ah, wait, is it okay to eat it?
And we still get more money from harvesting.
こぼー！
Kobo!
Hello, Kobo!
We're gonna become rich!
Alright, let's see...
I guess I technically don't have to put it in here, huh?
Alright, bring all the wheat.
Oh, there's more.
Oh...
Is there more wheat?
Okay.
And then, sell, sell, sell!
うーん、IDのゴルフ終わったかな？楽しそう、ゴルフ。
Hmm, is ID's golf over? Golf looks fun.
Did I forget to plant the wheat? I think I did.
Oh well, it's too late. Commit!
Oh yeah, the one on top of the house. I should.
Commit!
コスパ悪い。
Bad cost performance.
今、巣箱増やしてます。回収できない？
Right now, I'm increasing the beehives. Can't harvest them?
蜘蛛！うりゃ！うりゃ！
Spider! Take that! Take that!
More string, more fish.
買えるかも！
I might be able to buy it!
Nah.
買える。
I can buy it.
Ah!
Ah, 15...
いや、足りない...
No, not enough...
あ、買った。買ったぞ。
Ah, I bought it. I bought it!
買ったぞ。
I bought it!
Beetroot soup... Baked Potato...
Ah, bread... Ah, potato...
Okay, tomorrow I need eggs. たまご。And...
Okay, tomorrow I need eggs. Eggs, and...
And make bees, now that we got it. Every 30 minutes, I'm gonna check.
Oh, I did plant it, okay.
Get that.
まあ、ここでいいか。
Well, here is fine.
Okay.
Very slowly, it's gonna start working. And if I make enough money, we could probably get a second one to breed them...
...'cause we have quite a few of the bees.
Kaela, hello!
They're giving me strength.
I hope... I hope that tomorrow we can get at least one bee...
...that has a... that has a skill. That'd be nice.
You know, I'm- I'm starting to think there's no time to fish! Hahaha.
I'm starting to think there's no time to fish.
いや、でもなんか強いあれ、やりたいな。釣りして。
But, I want to do some strong thing with fishing.
なんか、なんとなく強い...
I feel like a strong...
...いいと思うけど。
...would be good, though.
いや、もう...
Well, already...
15分残ったから...
Since there are 15 minutes left...
ちょっとだけ釣りしてもいいかな？
...can I fish just a little bit?
ちょっとだけ、釣りしてもいいかな？
Can I fish just a little bit?
エンチャント本出るかもしれないし、強い...
An enchanted book might come out, or a strong...
これが、釣れるかもしれないし。
...I might catch this.
な？
Right?
ふぐ。
Pufferfish.
そういえば、クエスト忘...
By the way, I forgot about the quest...
クエスト忘れたんですけど！
I forgot about the quest!
クエスト忘れた！
I forgot the quest!
あ、いい。クエスト...
Ah, fine. Quest...
え、どこ？どこ？
Eh, where? Where?
どこにあるのかな？
Where is it?
どこだったっけ？
Where was it again?
いや、もう作ってるから、あの、行く場所は。
No, I've already made the place to go.
いや、やばい、やばい。
No, this is bad, this is bad.
何だっけ？What was the coordinate?
What was it? What was the coordinate?
17? -17?
まっすぐに行けるから。
Since I can go straight.
あれ？
Huh?
18。この辺でいい？いいんじゃない？
18. Is around here good? Isn't it fine?
16。
16.
いや...
Oh...
ちょっと、やばいかも。いや、でも絶対にやるよな。ここ、ここで。
This might be a bit bad. No, but I'll definitely do it. Here, in this place.
あー！
Ah!
うーん、どうしよう。行ってみる？
Hmm, what should I do? Should I go take a look?
ここ絶対、絶対にあるよ。
There's definitely, definitely some here.
暗い。
It's dark.
痛っ、痛っ！
Ow, ow!
あー！
Ah!
I ought to make a shield.
いや、絶対にあると思うんだけどな...
I really think there's got to be some here...
この辺... ないですか？
Around here... is there really none?
いや、ないですか？
No, is there really none?
やばい、宿題忘れた。
Oh no, I forgot about my homework.
釣りしたかった...
I wanted to go fishing...
いや、鉄なんですけど...
No, I need iron...
あ！
Ah!
できたー！
I did it!
ふー、宿題終わり。
Phew, homework's done.
Be our guest.
ひょー、ひょー。
Hyo~, hyo~.
じゃ、戻ろっか。
Well, let's head back.
戻って...
Head back, and...
ちょっとだけ、釣りしましょう。
Let's fish for just a little bit.
釣り、釣り...
Fishing, fishing...
あ、こっち。釣り、釣り...
Ah, this way. Fishing, fishing...
いや、明日の宿題は何が... おおっ。
I wonder what tomorrow's homework... Oh!
明日の宿題は何が出るかな？
I wonder what tomorrow's homework will be?
釣り、釣り、釣り、釣り...
Fishing, fishing, fishing, fishing...
釣り、釣り、釣り...
Fishing, fishing, fishing...
はぁー、いいですね。
Ah, this is nice.
ふぅー。
Phew.
お金、どれくらい貰えるんだっけ、釣りで？
How much money do we get from fishing again?
It's 77 right now.
おおー。
Oh~
Not bad.
Actually, I'm catching it faster than I thought.
Actually, the rate of fish is not bad at all.
I think the... it has been sped up a little bit.
あれ？
Huh?
お？
Oh?
どこから？
Where's that coming from?
For free... Oh, is it a reward for the quest?
First.
Oh, wait!
私の...
My...
I mean, as a farmer, you can have a maximum of, what was it, three?
So I could have one more. I think, I think we should have one more.
Now I have two. I'll get more bees.
It's just... yeah.
I don't know what I would have used it on otherwise, other than gambling.
Double the bees.
Four minutes, though.
And fish.
Wait, could we also sell fish, too? I don't remember.
I think so.
つり、つり、つり、つり、つり、つり、つり、つり、つり...
Fishing, fishing, fishing, fishing, fishing, fishing, fishing, fishing, fishing...
Oh!
A bottle of water.
I got a bottle of water.
Yeah.
Bottle of water.
あ、夜になる。
Ah, it's becoming night.
Maybe I should make a fishing shack.
So I'm unbothered while I fish...
...at the end of the day, after a long day of earning moneys.
A small dock...
...to be unbothered and fish.
Okay, I will leave at 59 so that nothing bugs out when the server closes.
Okay, one more fish, one more fish.
That should be it, 59.
Okay.
Nice!
Anyways...
I shall wrap it up here for today!
Thank you very much, everyone, for keeping me company.
見に来てくれてありがとうございました。
Thank you very much for coming to watch.
いや、枕... 枕... 枕だってもいいんじゃないですか？
Yeah, pillow... pillow... even a pillow would be fine, wouldn't it?
Oh, maybe I should have made myself glow.
まあ、じゃあ、また明日。
Well then, see you tomorrow.
釣りしましょう。
Let's do some fishing.
I shall see you guys tomorrow, for hopefully a little more fishing!
But it was fun, it was fun.
Anyways, thank you. Until next time, take care.
Bye-bye!
Wah!